本字幕由志愿者义务贡献，采用许可协议
知识共享 署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享 3.0 美国
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
>> All right, well, welcome to Stanford CS193P,
欢迎参加 2017 年冬季学期斯坦福
Developing Applications for iOS, winter of 2017.
在2017年冬天开发iOS应用。
CS193P 课程，iOS 应用程序开发
CS193P课程,iOS应用程序开发
This is Lecture number 9.
这是第九讲。
And today we have only one topic which is Table View.
今天我们只有一个主题是Table View。
And I'm gonna go through a bunch of slides to talk about
我要讲一大堆幻灯片
the concepts of it.
它的概念。
And then we're gonna have a humongous demo
然后我们会有一个巨大的演示
that we're gonna build a Twitter client and
我们要建立一个Twitter客户端
it's gonna use Table View and
它将使用表格视图
some other things that we've learned, like Text Field.
还有一些我们学过的东西，比如文本框。
And Table View, what is it?
表格视图，它是什么?
You've seen a Table View in all sorts of iOS apps.
你已经在各种iOS应用中看到了一个表视图。
It's just this UI where there's a list of things.
它只是这个UI，这里有一个列表。
There's really two different kinds of looks to Table View.
有两种不同类型的表视图。
There's the kind on the left there,
左边是这样的，
which we call plain style.
我们称之为普通风格。
Plain style is just a list of things.
简单的风格只是一份清单。
And it might be collected into groups like little sections.
它可能会被收集成小组，比如小段。
But it's mostly just a big long list.
但它大多只是一个长长的列表。
On the right side, is called a grouped style.
在右边，称为分组样式。
Where the sections in the table,
在表格中，
you're more obviously disconnected from each other.
你们之间的联系更加明显。
They have you know, big gaps in between.
他们之间有很大的差距。
Normally the plain style we use for dynamic data.
通常我们使用的是动态数据的普通样式。
Data that might have any number of items in there.
数据可能包含任意数量的项。
The group style we tend to use for static data,
我们倾向于使用的组样式用于静态数据，
where we know exactly what rows are gonna be in there,
我们确切知道哪行是，
and exactly what's gonna be in them.
他们到底会发生什么。
So let's talk about the names of all the parts of
我们来讨论一下所有部分的名称
a Table View, so that as I'm explaining all this,
一个表格视图，当我解释这些的时候，
you'll know what the terminology is.
你会知道术语是什么。
First we have a table header.
首先我们有一个表格标题。
That's a UIView.
这是一个UIView。
There's only one of them.
只有一个。
It sits at the very top of the table.
它位于桌子的最顶端。
This is where, as you'll see in the demo,
你们会在演示中看到，
you might put a search field or something that searches
你可能会放一个搜索栏或者搜索
to find what's in your table or something like that.
来看看你的桌子上有什么。
And similarly, there's a footer view.
类似地，还有一个footer view。
Rarely see this used.
很少看到这种使用。
But it's just a UIView that sits at the bottom
但它只是一个位于底部的UIView
And in between, there are these things called sections.
在这两者之间，有一些叫做节的东西。
of the table.
的表。
So a section is just a combination of a header and
所以section只是一个header和
a footer, which are usually strings, but
一个页脚，通常是字符串，但是
also could be UIViews, and then any number of rows.
也可以是uiview，然后是任意数量的行。
That's what we call a section.
这就是我们所说的section。
So that's a section right there.
这是一个部分。
This is the section header for the two sections that I have
这是我所拥有的两个部分的页眉
showing in this table, right, where it says Header 0.
显示在这个表中，它说的是Header 0。
And these are sections footers for
这些是页脚
the two sections that I have.
我有两个部分。
These two sections happen to both have the same numbers of
这两个部分的数量相等
rows in each which is two but a section, one section have
每一行有两行，但一节，一节有
a 100 rows, and one could have just 1, it's perfectly fine.
100行，1可以是1，很好。
This right in here, we call a table cell.
在这里，我们调用一个表格单元格。
C-E-L-L, cell, and it's the UIView,
c - e - l - l,cell，它是UIView，
actually UITableViewCell,
实际上UITableViewCell,
it's the name of the subclass that's in there.
它是这里的子类的名字。
And this is the thing that's gonna draw the data that's at
这就是要绘制数据的地方
a particular row.
一个特定的行。
And we're gonna see how that works.
我们将会看到它是如何运作的。
By the way, along the bottom you're seeing source code that
顺便说一下，在底部你看到的是源代码
kind of corresponds with these things.
类似于这些东西。
Don't worry I'm gonna get back to showing you all that stuff
别担心，我会回来给你看这些东西的
in later slides.
在后面的幻灯片。
So this is the naming we use to name all the parts of
这是命名，我们用它来命名所有的部分
a table view.
一个表格视图。
And this is in plain style.
这是朴素的风格。
All the same names work in group style.
所有相同的名称都以组的方式工作。
Everything just kinda looks a little different.
每件事看起来都有点不同。
All right, still have a header, footer,
好的，还有页眉，页脚，
sections, all the same.
部分,都是一样的。
Just a little different UI look.
只是一种不同的UI外观。
Now, tables can have sections or not.
现在，表格可以有分段。
You don't have to have any sections, so
你不需要有任何部分，所以
the table on the left is just a whole list of cities and
左边的桌子仅仅是一个城市的列表
the countries they're in and just a big long list.
他们所在的国家，只是一个长长的名单。
On the right is kind of the same kind of list but
右边是同样的列表
you can see that they're grouped into sections there by
你可以看到它们被分成了几个部分
country, right.
国家,对吧。
So Japan there, Mexico, etc.
日本，墨西哥等等。
So sections are optional,
所以部分是可选的,
not optional in the case of an option, but
在选项的情况下不是可选的，但是
sections you can have them or not, it's totally up to you.
你可以选择的部分，完全取决于你。
The type of the cell, like each row, there are four
单元格的类型，比如每一行，有四个
kinda pre-defined types and then there's a custom type.
有预定义类型，然后有自定义类型。
The four pre-defined types are subtitle where you just got
四个预定义类型是您刚刚得到的子标题
like a title and
像一个标题和
a little smaller text subtitle under it.
在它下面有一个小的文本副标题。
There's default which is the same except
默认情况下，除了
there's no little subtitle thing.
没有什么副标题。
There's value 1 and value 2, which is just like subtitle,
有值1和值2，就像副标题一样，
it's just that the little thing underneath is in
只是下面的小东西在里面
a different spot, it's either blue and
一个不同的点，要么是蓝色的，要么是
to the left or it's kind of grayed off into the right but
向左或向右偏
i's just how i's laying out the basic information there.
我只是在这里列出基本信息。
Now a custom cell can have arbitrary UI
现在自定义单元格可以有任意的UI
in it as you will see.
就像你看到的那样。
So how do we use a table view?
那么如何使用表格视图呢?
Okay, a table view is a UIView,
好的，一个表视图是一个UIView，
i's actually subclass UIScrollView because i's
我实际上是子类UIScrollView，因为
scrolling through all those rows.
滚动所有这些行。
Well 99% of the time, we use the special ViewController
99%的时候，我们使用特殊的ViewController
So how do we do it?
那我们该怎么做呢?
called UITableViewController in UIKit.
叫UITableViewController UIKit。
And UITableViewController is just a convenient package to
UITableViewController只是一个方便的包
use UITableView in and its self.view is a UITableView.
使用UITableView和它的self。视图是一个UITableView。
Okay, so you would only use a UITableViewController
你只能使用UITableViewController
when your entire self.view is going to be filled
当你的整个自我。视图将被填充
with a table view.
表视图。
And you can add one into your storyboard just by dragging it
你可以通过拖动添加一个到故事板中
out as we always do.
一如既往。
There's a thing called Table View Controller and
有一个东西叫表视图控制器
it's just gonna drag it out.
把它拖出来。
Now it's a controller, so when you drag it out,
现在它是一个控制器，当你把它拖出来的时候，
it looks like an MVC.
它看起来像一个MVC。
But inside of that MVC,
但是在MVC内部，
there is a table view sitting there, okay?
这里有一个表视图?
And so what you see here the controller,
你在这里看到的是控制器，
is a UITableViewController,
是一个UITableViewController,
and the self.view of it is a UITableView.
和自我。视图是一个UITableView。
Okay, subclass of UIScrollView.
好的,UIScrollView的子类。
Now like any other ViewController,
和其他视图控制器一样，
if you're going to do anything with this thing,
如果你想做任何事，
you need to subclass it, right?
你需要子类化它，对吧?
Just like you create a calculator view controller or
就像你创建计算器视图控制器一样
graph view controller,
图视图控制器,
you need to subclass, your UITableViewController as well.
你需要对UITableViewController进行子类化。
And you do it the same way, right?
你也用同样的方法，对吧?
New files are created.
创建新文件。
It's gonna be a Cocoa Touch Class of course.
当然是Cocoa Touch类。
It's gonna be a subclass of UITableViewController.
它是UITableViewController的子类。
Make sure you pick that.
一定要选那个。
Don't say it's a subclass of UIViewController.
不要说它是UIViewController的子类。
It has to be a subclass UITableViewController if you
它必须是一个子类UITableViewController
want it to work.
想要的工作。
And then you just set it in the identity inspector
然后你把它设置为身份检查器
Just exactly like any other controllers, just that it has
和其他控制器完全一样，只是它有
to be your class.
你的课。
to be subclass UITableViewController.
UITableViewController子类。
This UITableViewController subclass
这UITableViewController子类
is also going to serve as the data source and delegates.
也将作为数据源和委托。
Okay, the data source is just a special kind of delegate for
数据源只是一种特殊的委托
getting the data in the table.
获取表中的数据。
For the table view that's inside of it.
对于表视图，它的内部。
So, we're gonna talk a lot more about that
所以，我们会更多地讨论这个问题
down the road here.
这里的道路。
By the way, if you right click on the view controller and
顺便说一下，如果你右键点击视图控制器
you get that black window to come up, you can actually see
你可以看到那个黑色的窗口
it, if you look down towards the bottom there,
它，如果你向下看，
you see data source and delegate.
您可以看到数据源和委托。
Their properties and they're pre wired up for you.
他们的财产和他们预先为你准备好了。
If you use this UITableViewController thing,
如果你使用这个UITableViewController，
just pre-wires it up.
只是pre-wires起来。
That the controller is the delegate and
控制器是委托
data source of the table view.
表视图的数据源。
If you don't use UITableViewController,
如果你不使用UITableViewController，
by the way, this kinda pre-packaged one?
顺便问一下，这是预包装的吗?
Then you'll have to wire up the data source and
然后你需要将数据源连接起来
delegate, you know, either in code by saying
委托，你知道，可以用代码来表示
tableView.delegate = self or something like that.
表视图。委托= self之类的。
You'll have to do it yourself but 99% of the time you're
你必须自己做，但99%的时间都是这样
just gonna use this UITableViewController.
使用这个UITableViewController。
Cuz usually the best UI for a table view, is for
对于表视图来说，Cuz通常是最好的UI
it to take over the whole screen.
它占据了整个屏幕。
For it to fill the whole screen, it's rare that you can
为了填补整个屏幕，你很少能做到
have a table view in part of your screen.
在你的屏幕上有一个表视图。
So you can edit the attributes of the table view itself,
你可以编辑表格视图本身的属性，
of course, by just clicking on it and
当然，只要点击它就可以了
bringing up the attributes inspector.
打开属性检查器。
One thing that's a little frustrating about a table view
有一件事有点让人沮丧
is you've got the table view cells, which are UIViews.
你有表视图单元格，它们是uiview。
And then you've got the table view kind of that they're
然后你就得到了表格视图
contained in.
包含在。
That's a UIView also.
这是一个UIView也。
And then you've got the table view controller behind it.
然后你就有了表视图控制器。
And you wanna set attributes on all of these things.
你想要在所有这些东西上设置属性。
So don't forget you can do Ctrl+Shift+Left-click, and
所以别忘了你可以Ctrl + Shift +左击，还有
it'll put up a little menu.
它会放一个小菜单。
Says, okay, what thing under the mouse do you want?
说，好吧，你想要什么东西?
Do you want the cell, the table view, or the controller?
你想要单元格，表视图，还是控制器?
And so that'll help you dig down to the thing you want.
这样你就能找到你想要的东西。
All right, but once you have it selected,
好的，但是一旦你选择了它，
whichever one you want, like the TableView or
不管你想要哪个，比如TableView
the Controller or the Cell, you can inspect it of course.
控制器或单元格，当然可以检查。
Now, one important thing is this grouped versus plain that
现在，有一件很重要的事情是这一组对比普通的
I showed you at the very beginning.
我一开始就给你们看过。
So here I'm gonna switch this one which is plain
我要把这个换成普通的
over to grouped.
分组。
So I'm just picking grouped in the style there,
所以我只是按照这里的样式进行分组，
in the inspector.
检查员。
Another important attribute is dynamic versus static.
另一个重要的属性是动态与静态。
So dynamic is all the contents are coming from some database.
动态是所有内容都来自于数据库。
And static is, I'm gonna put all the content right here in
我将把所有内容放到这里
the story board, okay?
这个故事,好吗?
So here we'll switch this one over to static.
我们把这个换成静态的。
So this is now a static, grouped table view.
这是一个静态的，分组的表格视图。
And I told you that usually static table views
我讲过静态表格视图
are grouped, and usually only grouped ones are static.
分组，通常只有分组的是静态的。
So usually these kinda go together.
通常这些都是结合在一起的。
They don't have to, they're separate properties, but
它们不需要，它们是分开的属性，但是
they generally go together.
他们通常一起去。
Now the UI for these rows, most of the time you're
这些行的UI，大部分时间都是这样
just going to build by dragging UI in.
通过拖动UI来构建。
So here I'm just dragging the label in here, and you know,
我把标签拖到这里，
maybe I'll change the name of the label, dragging the UI
也许我会改变标签的名称，拖拽UI
switch in there, cuz I want to set up some settings.
切换到这里，因为我想设置一些设置。
Often times, by the way, this thing is used for settings and
通常情况下，这个东西是用来设置的
things like that.
类似这样的事情。
And then if I want to talk to these switches and
如果我想和这些开关对话
labels that I brought in there, I'm actually gonna
我带来的标签，我将会
create outlets to my UITableViewController.
为我的UITableViewController创建outlet。
And since what's in this table is fixed for
因为这张桌子上的东西是固定的
all time in the storyboard.
所有时间都在故事板中。
I'm building it in a storyboard,
我在故事板中构建它，
that's perfectly fine.
就很好了。
So I would just Ctrl + drag from them to my controller,
我将Ctrl +拖动到控制器中，
which will work, and then I can create an outlet for
这是可行的，然后我可以创建一个outlet for
example, my feature enabled switch outlet and
例如，我的功能启用了开关插座
it'll create an outlet here.
它会在这里创建一个outlet。
And then in my code and my controller,
然后在我的代码和控制器中，
I can obviously do whatever I want to that switch.
我可以做任何我想做的事情。
So, it's almost like when you have a static table view, it's
它就像你有一个静态表格视图
almost just like a normal view that you would build UI in.
就像一般的视图一样，你可以创建UI。
It's just that it's divided into these rows.
只是它被分成了这些行。
Which is nice for something like settings, right?
这对设置来说很好，对吧?
If you think about the settings app, right,
如果你想想设置app，对吧，
on your phone.
在你的手机上。
It's got a lot of UI that's kind of in rows right, and
它有很多UI，在行右边
in tables.
在表中。
So, if you really wanna see how static table view works,
如果你想看看静态表格视图是如何工作的，
get your phone out, go to the general settings app and
把你的手机拿出来，去通用设置应用程序
just look around in there.
随便看看。
That is table view after table view after table view where
这是表视图之后的表格视图
the rows are static built in some storyboard somewhere by
这些行是静态构建在某个故事板中的某个地方
Apple.
苹果。
All right, so that's pretty much it for static table.
这差不多就是静态表格的内容了。
These are pretty straightforward to do.
这些都很简单。
So I'm gonna clear this UI out of here,
我要把这个UI清除掉，
this featured enabled out of there, then we're gonna talk
这个功能被激活了，然后我们会讨论
about a different kind of table view, which is dynamic.
关于另一种表视图，它是动态的。
So a dynamic table view, you set it here by picking dynamic
一个动态表格视图，你可以通过选择动态来设置它
property, prototypes, rather, there instead of static cells,
属性，原型，而不是静态单元，
really is a totally different kind of animal, and
真的是一种完全不同的动物，而且
I'm gonna switch back to plain style because usually dynamic
我要切换回普通样式，因为通常是动态的
tables are plain style.
表是简单的风格。
These rows now instead of being something you're
这些行现在不是你的
gonna build the UI and
来构建UI
they're static, instead they're prototypes.
它们是静态的，而不是原型。
They're things that are gonna be copied for every row.
它们是每一行都要复制的东西。
So whatever UI you would build in one of these rows.
所以无论你在其中一个行中构建什么UI。
And you can build customize UI,
你可以建立自定义UI，
like we saw with the static one.
就像我们看到的静态的。
It's gonna be copied for every single row.
它会被复制到每一行。
So these are prototypes.
这是原型。
You see what I mean by prototype?
你明白我所说的原型吗?
It's like a template that's gonna be copied over and
它就像一个模板，复制过来
over and over to make your table.
一遍又一遍地做你的桌子。
So that's a really different kind of
所以这是一个非常不同的类型
way of looking at things.
看待事物的方式。
Because this data that's gonna go into these rows is
因为这些数据会进入这些行
coming from some database somewhere probably and
可能来自某个数据库
filling out all this information.
填写所有这些信息。
So it's a little more complicated to build
所以建造起来有点复杂
a table like this, but not a lot more.
像这样的桌子，但不是很多。
So you can click on any one of the cells and
你可以点击任何一个单元格
you can inspect it, right?
你可以检查一下，对吧?
The prototypes that you want.
你想要的原型。
For example you could change its type from being custom
例如，您可以更改它的类型自定义
to being subtitle.
副标题。
All right, so here's what a subtitle cell looks like.
好了，这就是一个subtitle cell的样子。
Remember I showed you in the very second slide,
记得我在第二张幻灯片中给你们看的，
it's one of the pre-canned types.
它是预定型的类型之一。
And it just has, you know,
它只是，你知道，
a text field, like a little smaller text field.
文本字段，像小一点的文本字段。
So that's a subtitle.
这是一个副标题。
You can also set with accessory there,
你也可以在那里设置附件，
a little thing that can appear on the right.
右边会出现一些小东西。
It could be a little check mark that you turn on and off.
它可以是一个你打开和关闭的检查标志。
It could be a disclosure indicator,
它可能是一个信息披露指标，
which you want to put there if clicking on this row is going
如果点击这一行，你想把它放在哪里
to segue.
segue。
Okay, that little disclosure indicator is just a little,
好吧，这个小小的披露指标只是一点点，
kind of gray arrow thing that lets the user know,
一种灰色的箭头让用户知道，
hey if I click on this row, it's going to segue.
如果我点击这一行，它就会segue。
There's also kind of a special one called detail disclosure.
还有一种特殊的叫做细节披露。
And the detail disclosure looks like this,
细节披露是这样的，
it's a little "i" in a circle.
这是一个圆圈里的小“i”。
And what's really cool about that is you can segue by
很酷的一点是你可以通过segue
clicking on the row, but if you click on the little blue
点击这一行，但如果你点击蓝色的小图标
I, it does a different segue.
我，它有一个不同的segue。
Okay, so you kind of have your row doing two different
好了，你可以做两种不同的行
segues, depending on whether they touch on the little i or
segue，取决于它们是接触到这个小的i还是
touch somewhere else.
联系别的地方。
You see the little gray arrow next to the i?
你看到我旁边的小灰箭了吗?
That's the disclosure indicator.
这就是信息披露指标。
So if I click on this row, it's going to segue.
如果我点击这一行，它就会segue。
If I click on the little i,
如果我点击这个小的I，
it's gonna do some different segue.
它会做一些不同的segue。
Maybe bring up some modal panel with some information or
也许会带一些信息或者是一些模式
something like that.
就像这样。
We'll talk about how that works in a second.
我们一会儿会谈到它是如何工作的。
All right, so I'm gonna go back to non-details,
好了，回到非细节部分，
go ahead and get rid of that thing.
去把那个东西删掉。
But another style besides the four pre-canned
但另一种风格除了四种预装
ones I talked about in the beginning of this lecture
我在这节课开始的时候讲过
that you can pick is custom.
你可以选择的是习惯。
So custom means that, that's just a UIView,
所以自定义意味着，这只是一个UIView，
that you can build any UI you want.
你可以构建任何你想要的UI。
Again similar to that feature-enabled
类似于功能特性
with the switch that I showed.
用我刚才展示的开关。
But again, this UI is going to get copied over and
但同样，这个UI会被复制过来
over and over for
一遍又一遍的
Notice, by the way, there are multiple prototypes.
注意，顺便说一下，有多个原型。
That means you can have different setups of UI
这意味着您可以有不同的UI设置
that you could use for different rows, okay?
你可以使用不同的行?
And we're gonna name each of these prototypes so
我们要给每一个原型命名
that in our code, we can pick which prototype we want for
在我们的代码中，我们可以选择我们想要的原型
a certain row.
一定行。
It will copy that prototype.
它会复制原型。
Now, these custom cells, you can resize them.
现在，这些自定义单元格，可以调整大小。
You can drag stuff into them, build UI you want.
你可以把东西拖进去，你想要的UI。
Here, I've built this complicated UI with text
这里，我用文本构建了这个复杂的UI
fields and an image.
字段和一个图像。
This is very similar to a UI that I'm gonna build in
这和我要构建的UI非常类似
All right, now when you build this UI you're gonna want
当你创建这个UI时，你需要
the demo.
这个演示。
to use proper layout.
使用适当的布局。
So stack views and hooking it to the edges just like you did
就像你一样，把视图叠加到边缘
with the calculator or even stuff on the inside.
用计算器或者内部的东西。
I'll show you a little bit of that today,
我今天会给你们展示一点，
a little more auto layout.
多一点自动布局。
Because if you do that, then the table view will be able to
因为如果你这样做，表格视图就能
figure out the size this thing needs to be dynamically.
计算出这个东西需要动态的大小。
Okay, if you don't do the right auto layout then you
如果你不做正确的自动布局
kind of just have to fix the height of the rows, and
只需要修改行的高度
I'm going to talk about that in a minute as well.
我一会儿也会讲到这个。
So generally you want to do auto layout properly
一般来说，你想要正确的自动布局
in there if you can.
如果可以的话，在那里。
Now ther's no way I could wire up these
我不可能把它们连接起来
elements directly to my controller.
元素直接到我的控制器。
Do you see why?
你知道为什么吗?
Because ther's only one outlet in my controller for
因为在我的控制器中，这里只有一个outlet
one of these labels.
这些标签之一。
But there are hundreds of rows.
但有数百行。
So how is my one outlet gonna?
那么我的一个出口会怎样呢?
It can't be hooked up to 100 at once, okay.
它不能一次连接到100，好的。
But I still need outlets because how am I gonna
但我仍然需要媒体，因为我要怎么做
set these things?
设置这些东西?
All right, and so
好吧,所以
the way we're gonna deal with that is we're gonna wire these
我们要处理的方法是把这些线连接起来
things up to outlets in the UITableViewCell.
到UITableViewCell中的outlet。
The UIView that contains them.
包含它们的UIView。
So I told you that this cell is a UIView,
我告诉你这个单元格是一个UIView，
a UITableViewCell, and it contains all of these things,
一个UITableViewCell，它包含所有这些东西，
these labels and stuff.
这些标签等等。
So, we're gonna have outlets in that.
因此，我们会有outlet。
Now this is the first time you've ever seen
这是你第一次看到
outlet in anything but a controller and pretty much
除了控制器和几乎所有的插座
this is the only other time you're gonna have outlets.
这是你唯一的其他时间。
You can't have outlets in a regular view, but
你不能在常规视图中有outlet，但是
you can have outlets in these special table view cells.
您可以在这些特殊的表视图单元格中有outlet。
All right, so let's see a little bit of how that works.
好的，让我们来看看它是如何工作的。
So, one thing, if you're gonna have outlets,
有一件事，如果你有outlet，
you know you're gonna need to have subclass, right?
你知道你需要有子类，对吧?
Just like you have a controller, you can't use
就像你有一个控制器，你不能使用
a generic UIViewController, can't put any outlets in that;
一个通用的UIViewController，不能在其中放置任何outlet;
you have to subclass it so you can wire out, same thing here.
你必须把它子类化，这样你就可以把它连接起来，就像这里一样。
You're gonna have to make a custom subclass,
你需要创建一个自定义子类，
a UITableViewCell.
UITableViewCell。
You do that with New File.
你用新文件来做。
It is still a Cocoa Touch Class, but here you're going
它仍然是一个Cocoa触摸类，但在这里
to choose UITableViewCell as the super class,
选择UITableViewCell作为超类，
not UITableViewController.
不是UITableViewController。
UITableViewCell.
UITableViewCell。
And again UITableViewCell is a subclass of UIView also,
UITableViewCell也是UIView的一个子类，
All right, so you're going to pick a UITableViewCell,
好了，你要选择一个UITableViewCell，
by the way.
顺便说一下。
call it something like MyTableViewCell or whatever.
就像MyTableViewCell之类的。
And then you're gonna do the exact same thing where you're
然后你会做同样的事情
gonna have that cell selected.
会选择这个单元格。
And you're gonna go to the identity inspector.
你要去找身份检查官。
And you're gonna change it from being a generic
你要把它变成一般的
UITableViewCell to being MyTableViewCell.
UITableViewCell MyTableViewCell。
And this is gonna allow you to create outlets
这将允许你创建outlet
In MyTableViewCell to these things that are contained
在MyTableViewCell中包含这些内容
inside MyTableViewCell.
MyTableViewCell内部。
Okay, so now we can wire them up.
现在我们可以把它们连接起来。
So remember that static elements,
记住，静态元素，
those things I showed you at the beginning,
我刚开始给你们看的那些东西，
those are wired up to the controller.
这些都连接到控制器。
Dynamic elements, where we have these prototypes,
动态元素，我们有这些原型，
those are wired up to the TableViewCell outlets.
这些被连接到TableViewCell outlet。
So what does it look like to wire them up?
把它们连接起来会是什么样子呢?
I'm gonna have to do the same thing with the controller
我要对控制器做同样的事情
where I'm gonna get the UI and the code on screen
我要在屏幕上得到UI和代码
at the same time with the assistant editor.
与助理编辑在同一时间。
By the way, when you do that, if you're in automatic mode,
顺便说一下，如果你在自动模式下，
there, see where it says automatic?
看到了吗，自动的?
It's pointing at automatic.
它是指向自动。
It's not going to bring up the UITableViewCell, even if you
它不会打开UITableViewCell，即使你
have the TableViewCell selected in the UI.
在UI中选择TableViewCell。
It's still gonna bring up the controller, okay?
它还是会弹出控制器?
So if you want to wire up outlets to a TableViewCell,
如果你想把outlet到TableViewCell，
you have to manually or
你必须手动或
forcibly get that TableViewCell- not
强制获取TableViewCell——不是
the TableViewController- TableViewCell, on this side.
TableViewCell，在这边。
So one way you can do it is by switching from Automatic
一种方法是，从自动开始
to Manual and then navigating over to finding your
手动，然后导航到找到你的
TableViewCell.swift class, right?
TableViewCell。斯威夫特类,对吧?
And then choosing that.
然后选择。
And now you're in manual mode,
现在你处于手动模式，
you've got the TableViewCell on the right, and
右边是TableViewCell
you've got your storyboard on the left.
你的故事板在左边。
So, now you can Ctrl+drag, right?
现在可以Ctrl +拖动，对吧?
You just need to be able to Ctrl+drag
你只需要能够Ctrl +拖动
between them is the problem.
问题就在他们之间。
So you gotta have them both on screen.
所以你要把它们都放在屏幕上。
All right, so then, once I have them on screen,
好的，一旦我把它们放到屏幕上，
I Ctrl+drag, just absolutely normally.
Ctrl +拖动，非常正常。
And it's gonna do all the things that an outlet does,
它会做所有outlet做的事情，
it's gonna ask me, an outlet or action.
它会问我，一个出口或动作。
By the way, you can do outlet or action here.
顺便说一下，你可以在这里做出口或动作。
And it's gonna ask.
会问。
So here, I've picked that photo, the blue thing.
这里，我选了这张照片，蓝色的。
Let's say it's a photo.
假设这是一张照片。
And I'm calling this my photoImageView.
这是我的photoImageView。
And it creates an outlet here.
它在这里创建一个outlet。
Okay, so that's great.
好了,这很好。
Now this TableViewCell code can talk to that photo.
现在这个TableViewCell代码可以与这张照片对话。
The ImageView could for example set the image or
例如，ImageView可以设置图像或
whatever.
无论什么。
But of course it needs to know what information to put
但当然，它需要知道要输入什么信息
in that photo for that row, right?
在这张照片里，对吧?
This thing is gonna be repeated 100 times, and
这个东西会重复100次
each one needs to know what its row's photo is.
每个人都需要知道它的row的照片是什么。
So you're also gonna need some public API on your
所以你也需要一些公共API
TableViewCell which gives it the data it needs to fill up
TableViewCell，它需要填充数据
all its outlets.
所有的媒体。
Okay, so you're gonna have some var, which I've
你会得到一些var
called infoShownByThisCell, could be of any type you want.
这个单元名为infoshownbythis cell，可以是任何你想要的类型。
And somebody is gonna set it, you'll see soon who sets it.
有人会设置它，你很快就会看到谁设置了它。
And once it sets it, now we can update the UI and
一旦设置好了，我们就可以更新UI了
put all this information into the outlets.
把所有这些信息都放进出口。
Okay, so this is how the information at each row in
这就是每一行的信息
the table is going to be put into these UI elements.
表将被放入这些UI元素中。
You all following me so far?
你们都跟上我了吗?
All right, let's talk about these two protocols,
好了，我们来谈谈这两个协议，
the dataSource and the delegate, okay.
数据源和委托，好的。
They're critical to making UITableView work.
它们对于进行UITableView的工作至关重要。
UITableView is a class that literally cannot function
UITableView是一个不能正常工作的类
without its dataSource and delegate.
没有数据源和委托。
It's not really like split view controller where, eh, you
它不像分视图控制器，呃，你
don't have to do anything with a delegate if you don't want,
如果你不想，就不必和委托做任何事情，
it'll still work.
它仍然会工作。
This, you really have to do it.
这，你真的必须这么做。
Especially the dataSource.
尤其是数据源。
If you don't give it a dataSource, the only
如果你不给它一个数据源，唯一的
way a table view would work without its delegate and
如果没有它的委托，表视图就可以工作
dataSource is if it were purely static table.
数据源是纯静态表。
Like the table that had the feature enabled with
就像启用了特性的表一样
the switch.
开关。
That you could deal without the dataSource.
你可以在没有数据源的情况下进行处理。
But otherwise, if it's providing dynamic data,
但如果它提供动态数据，
obviously it needs the data.
显然它需要数据。
And the only way it can get data is
它能得到数据的唯一方法是
through its dataSource.
通过它的数据源。
So, as I already told you, UITableViewController
正如我已经告诉你的，UITableViewController
automatically sets itself as its delegate and dataSource.
自动将自己设置为它的委托和数据源。
So you can just put your code for these delegate methods
你可以把你的代码放到这些委托方法中
right in your subclass of UITableViewController, right.
在UITableViewController的子类中，对。
MyTableViewController, or whatever, and put it in there.
MyTableViewController，把它放在这里。
Also, there's a cool var in TableViewController called
另外，TableViewController里有一个很酷的var
tableView, which is basically gonna return self.view, but
tableView，它会返回self。观点,但
as a UITableView.
UITableView。
And that way you can talk to the UITableView that your
这样你就可以和UITableView对话了
UITableViewController is controlling.
UITableViewController控制。
So when do we need to implement the dataSource?
那么，何时需要实现数据源呢?
Anytime we have dynamic data, non-static.
只要我们有动态数据，非静态数据。
There are three really important methods in this
这里有三个非常重要的方法
One is, how many sections are in my table?
一个是，表格中有多少个section ?
protocol.
协议。
Could be one section if the whole thing is just
如果整件事都是公正的，可以是一段吗
a bunch of rows.
一群行。
How many sections, and
有多少部分,和
then how many rows are in each section?
每个section中有多少行?
You're gonna be asked one by one.
你会被一个一个问。
How many rows in this section?
这一节有多少行?
How many rows in this section? How many are in this section?
这一节有多少行?这一节有多少?
So it knows how many rows are in every section.
它知道每个section中有多少行。
And then most importantly, give me one of those
最重要的是，给我一个
UITableViewCells to draw this row.
uitableviewcell来绘制这一行。
Okay, so for each row that the TableView wants to draw,
对于TableView想要绘制的每一行，
i's going to ask you, okay, give me a UITableViewCell now,
我要问你，给我一个UITableViewCell，
cuz I'm going to draw this row.
因为我要画这一行。
Okay, so that's how it works,
好的，这就是它的工作原理，
that's fundamentally how this works.
这就是它的基本原理。
Now, all these methods are in the UITableViewDataSource
现在，所有这些方法都在UITableViewDataSource中
protocol.
协议。
So let's look at the last one, the give me a UITableViewCell,
让我们看最后一个，给我一个UITableViewCell，
cuz it's the most complicated.
因为这是最复杂的。
The other ones are super, super simple.
其他的超级简单。
So the way that you are going to give a UITableViewCell
你要给UITableViewCell的方法
back to the TableView when it's time to draw a certain
回到TableView时，应该画一个
row is by a method being called.
row是被调用的方法。
Now, you might be worried here, it's like woah,
现在，你可能会担心，就像woah，
I'm gonna have this big UI with all these labels and
我要把这个大UI和所有这些标签
image views in it, and I have, what if I have 100,000 rows?
图像视图，如果我有10万行呢?
I'm going to make 100,000 views.
我将会有10万次视图。
Surely that's going to be terrible performance.
这肯定会很糟糕。
And in fact, that would be terrible performance, okay.
事实上，这将是糟糕的表现。
Views are not cheap.
观点是不便宜的。
But no worries, because all your UITableViewCells,
但不用担心，因为所有uitableviewcell，
these UIViews that draw the rows, they're reused.
这些UIViews绘制行，它们被重用。
So only the visible ones have UITableViewCells.
只有可见的有uitableviewcell。
As you scroll around, the ones that scroll off the top
当你滚动的时候，滚动到顶部的
get picked up and put around and used on the bottom, okay?
拿起，放在底部，好吗?
And the new data keeps getting pumped into them.
新的数据不断被注入。
Do you see what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思吗?
So those cells, only the,
这些细胞，
maybe the ones on the screen plus two or
也许屏幕上的是+ 2
three on either side are actually getting created.
两边的三个实际上是被创造出来的。
They're just getting reused.
他们只是得到重用。
As you scroll up and down, they keep getting reused.
当你上下滚动时，它们会不断重复使用。
Now, the thing about that reuse,
关于重用，
I want you to be very careful of.
我要你小心点。
I put it in red.
我把它涂成红色。
When I put it in red, you know that means wake up and
当我把它涂成红色的时候，你知道这意味着醒来
watch out, cuz your homework.
小心点，你的作业。
When you're doing multithreaded things,
当你做多线程的时候，
you've got to be careful,
你要小心，
because by the time you come back from something you asked
因为当你从你问的问题回来的时候
to do on another thread, your cell might be reused, okay.
要在另一个线程上执行，您的单元格可能会被重用。
And so you've got to be prepared for that.
所以你必须为此做好准备。
You gotta understand whether you're still the cell you
你必须明白你是否仍然是你的细胞
thought you were when you sent something off to go in
以为你是在送东西进去的时候
another thread.
另一个线程。
Okay, so I'm warning you.
好吧，我警告你。
So what does this method look like that the UITableView is
这个方法看起来像UITableView
gonna send to its data source to say,
发送到它的数据源说，
give me a UITableViewCell?
给我一个UITableViewCell ?
It's called cellForRowAt indexPath.
它被称为cellForRowAt indexPath。
You see it right there.
就在这里。
That's its signature.
这是它的签名。
It really only has that one argument, indexPath.
它只有一个参数，indexPath。
The indexPath is just a little container of
indexPath只是一个小容器
the section and row.
的部分和行。
You could imagine this is even called cellForRowAt
你可以想象这个被称为cellForRowAt
section and row.
部分和行。
But it just puts them in one argument called
但它只是把它们放在一个叫做
an indexPath, okay.
一个indexPath,好吧。
And then all you return is a UITableViewCell.
然后返回的是UITableViewCell。
And it's gonna use that UITableViewCell to draw
它将使用UITableViewCell来绘制
that row.
这一行。
So it really couldn't be a simpler API.
所以它真的不可能是一个简单的API。
It's at the heart of exactly what it's asking you to do.
这是它要求你做的事情的核心。
Now, what are you gonna do inside this method?
现在，你要在这个方法里做什么?
Well, first you're going to have to get the data from your
首先，你需要从你的数据中获取数据
model that you want to show in that row.
你想要在这一行显示的模型。
Okay.
好吧。
And you can do this any way you want.
你可以任意选择。
I have a very convenient data structure here called
我这里有一个非常方便的数据结构
myInternalDataStructure that happens to be divided
myInternalDataStructure，恰好被分割
in sections and rows.
在部分和行。
So I can just index into it.
所以我可以把它标出来。
But you might have a different data structure.
但你可能有不同的数据结构。
But you've gotta take the section and row so
但你得把这部分和行写出来
that you know which row you're talking about, and
你知道你在说哪行，和
get the data out of your model.
从模型中获取数据。
Maybe you're doing a database query.
也许你正在做一个数据库查询。
Maybe you're even doing a network query in another
也许你甚至在另一个网站上做一个网络查询
thread and it's gonna return and fill this out, whatever.
线程，它会返回并把它填满。
You need to figure out how to get your data.
你需要弄清楚如何得到你的数据。
Now, once you have your data, you're gonna create a cell.
现在，一旦你有了数据，你就会创建一个单元格。
I'm gonna show you how to do that in a second.
我马上就会告诉你们怎么做。
And then you're just gonna load up that cell
然后把这个单元格加载起来
with the data.
与数据。
So let's talk about how we create that cell and
我们来讨论一下如何创建这个单元格
So I'm gonna take this little piece of code, and
我要把这段代码写出来
load it up.
负载。
I'm gonna keep it on screen while I go back to showing you
我要把它放在屏幕上，当我回去给你们看的时候
what's happening in the UI here.
UI中发生了什么。
So first let's talk about a cell that's not a custom cell.
首先，我们来讨论一个单元格不是自定义单元格。
It's just a regular cell like subtitle.
它只是一个普通的单元格，如副标题。
You see subtitle up there?
上面有副标题吗?
Okay, so we're gonna use this method here called
我们将使用这个方法
dequeueReusableCell(withIdent- ifier: for: indexPath).
dequeueReusableCell(withIdent - ify::indexPath)。
And that's just gonna return us a UITableViewCell.
这将返回一个UITableViewCell。
Now, again, this is a reused UITableViewCell.
再一次，这是一个重复使用的UITableViewCell。
Okay, being reused,
好吧,被重用,
now if this cell, if there's not enough been created yet,
如果这个单元格还没有创建，
then it will create one based on your prototype.
然后它会根据你的原型创建一个。
Whatever your prototype you pick in there.
不管你的原型是什么。
And you pick which prototype with this string,
然后你选择了这个字符串的原型，
the identifier string
标识符的字符串
which you set in the inspector for the cell.
你把它设置为单元格的检查器。
So, it's just in there, it's called identifier,
它就在这里，叫做标识符，
the utilities inspector on the right is inspecting that cell,
右边的水电费检查员正在检查那间牢房，
that top cell that says title, subtitle,
顶部单元格表示标题，副标题，
it's inspecting that.
这是检查。
And I'm just setting the identifier of my cell, so
我只是设置了单元格的标识符
now in my code when I say, dequeueReuseableCellwithIdent-
现在在我的代码当我说,dequeueReuseableCellwithIdent -
ifier of MyCell, it's gonna make a copy of that prototype.
MyCell的ifier，它会复制这个原型。
Unless there's some to be reused,
除非有一些可以重复使用，
then it'll just reuse them.
然后它就会重新使用它们。
But until it gets enough to reuse,
但在它得到足够的重用之前，
it uses that prototype and
它使用了原型和
just makes copies of it as necessary.
只是在必要时复制它。
Now, this is a non-custom cell, so
这是一个非自定义单元格
the only, well there's a few fields you can set.
唯一的，嗯，你可以设置一些字段。
You can go look at the API for UITableViewCell to find out.
您可以查看UITableViewCell的API来了解它。
But the cell, set those two pieces of text, title and
但是单元格，设置了这两个文本，标题和
subtitle there.
副标题。
You just, you use textlabel.text and
你只需要使用textlabel。文本和
detailtextlabel.text.
detailtextlabel.text。
Those are optional, so they could be nil,
这些是可选的，所以它们可以是nil，
because if there's a custom cell, for
因为如果有自定义单元格
example, it might be nil.
例如，它可能是nil。
So anyway that's it, you just set those,
不管怎么说，你只要设置这些，
those are just UILabels.
这些只是uilabel。
And so you just set the text, it couldn't be easier.
所以你只要设置文本，就不容易了。
And that's true for
这是真的
all the pre-canned ones, you're gonna set these.
所有的pre -罐装的，你都要设置这些。
There is actually, I can show it, but there's an image also,
实际上，我可以展示它，但也有一个图像，
that you can set, a little image in the cell.
你可以在单元格里设置一个小图像。
And that's also in the pre-canned ones,
这也是在前罐装的，
so you could do that as well, okay?
你也可以这么做?
So that's it, that's just simple,
就是这样，很简单，
that's all you need to do to provide your data
这就是提供数据所需的全部内容
to the TableViewCell is just dequeue one of these cells.
对于TableViewCell，它只是dequeue，其中一个单元格。
Just load it up and return it, and
只要把它装上然后放回去
now the tableView will use that to draw.
现在tableView会用它来画。
But let's talk about a custom cell, so
我们来讨论一下自定义单元格
now I'm talking about the second row down.
现在我说的是第二排。
And look at its type,
看看它的类型，
it's custom- it's not subtitle- it's custom.
这是习俗，不是副标题，而是习俗。
Little different for a custom cell.
对于一个自定义单元来说，几乎没有什么不同。
You're still gonna do dequeueReusableCellwithIdenti-
你仍然要做dequeueReusableCellwithIdenti -
fier for index path, okay?
索引路径的人?
But of course you're going to use a different identifier,
当然，你要用一个不同的标识符，
cuz now I'm talking about the second cell down which I'm
因为我说的是第二个细胞
calling my custom cell.
叫我的自定义单元格。
Now here there's no title and subtitle in that second row.
在第二行中没有标题和副标题。
Presumably there's that image and
大概是这样的
the thing under text under it and text on the side.
它下面的文字和旁边的文字。
All the things, whatever your UI switch,
所有的东西，不管你的UI开关是什么，
whatever you built in this custom cell.
无论你在这个自定义单元格中构建了什么。
And all that stuff has got outlets hooked up to
所有这些东西都被连接起来
the UITableViewCell containing it, remember all that we did?
UITableViewCell包含它，记得我们做过的吗?
So you need to just pass the data to that UITableViewCell
所以你需要把数据传递给UITableViewCell
and it's responsible for loading up all the UI.
它负责加载所有UI。
Now how do you do that?
怎么做呢?
First thing you need to do is take that dequeued
你需要做的第一件事就是排队
thing that came back, which is of type UITableViewCell.
返回的是UITableViewCell的类型。
And cast it with "as" to be of
用“as”来表示
the type of your subclass of UITableViewCell.
UITableViewCell的子类的类型。
Otherwise you won't be able to call any of this API.
否则你就不能调用这个API。
Okay, so you're just gonna do, if I can let this cell equal
好，如果我能让这个单元格等于
the dequeued thing as MyTableViewCell.
de排队的东西是MyTableViewCell。
Then I'm going to talk to MyTableViewCell using its API
然后我将使用它的API与MyTableViewCell对话
and set, for example, infoShownByThisCell to be
并设置，例如，infoshownbythis cell
the data that's app that section in row.
这是应用程序的数据。
Okay, so to go back to the code I was showing before,
回到我刚才展示的代码，
that info shown by the cell is that var right there.
这个由细胞显示的信息就是这个var。
The var that I made public in MyTableViewCell.
我在MyTableViewCell中公开的var。
And then it's gonna update UI and set all of its outlets and
然后它会更新UI并设置所有的outlet和
all of that.
所有这些。
Okay, so that's it, that how it works.
好了，这就是它的工作原理。
Those are the two cases, the kind of pre-canned one and
这是两种情况，一种是预灌装的
the custom one.
自定义一个。
They're almost identical, you're still dequeuing cells,
它们几乎是一样的，你仍然在排长，
you just set the data a little bit differently.
你只是把数据设置得有点不同。
Okay, the data source also has to know how many sections and
好的，数据源还需要知道有多少分段
rows.
行。
It's really simple,
这很简单,
there's a method called numberOfSections in tableView.
tableView中有一种方法叫做numberofsection。
And that's going to return int,
它会返回int，
how many sections there are.
有多少节。
By the way that one is optional;
顺便说一下，这个是可选的;
you don't have to implement that one.
你不需要执行那个。
If you don't, it will assume there's one section,
如果你没有，它会假设有一个部分，
that all the rows are in this one big section.
所有的行都在这个大的section中。
The other one though, which is numberOfRowsInSection where it
另一个是，它是numberOfRowsInSection
passes you a section number, and
给你一个section号码，然后
you have to say how many rows are in the section.
你必须说出section中有多少行。
That is not optional,
这不是可选的,
that is mandatory, and you must answer this question for
这是强制性的，你必须回答这个问题
every single section that you claim that your table has
你声称你的表的每一个部分都有
with numberOfSections in table, okay?
表格中有numberofsection ?
So that's it, that's simple, why does it need to know how
这很简单，为什么需要知道
many rows and all of the sections, by the way?
还有很多行和所有的部分?
Cuz it's a scroll view and it needs to know how big a thing,
因为它是一个滚动视图，它需要知道一个东西有多大，
it needs to set it's content size basically, right?
它需要设置它的内容大小，对吧?
It needs to know how big a thing it's scrolling over, so
它需要知道滚动的东西有多大，所以
it needs to know.
它需要知道。
But it also needs to know when to ask you for the data and
但它也需要知道什么时候向你询问数据
all that, so it's pretty obvious it needs to know that.
所有这些，很明显它需要知道。
In a static table by the way,
在静态表格中，
it's not gonna ask you these questions.
我不会问你这些问题。
So don't even worry about that.
所以不要担心这个。
The static table is fixed in the StoryBoard, so
静态表在故事板中是固定的
it's never asking you for the data.
它从来不要求你提供数据。
So it's never gonna ask you how many rows and sections and
所以它不会问你有多少行和节
all that stuff there is.
所有这些都是。
So the summary is you set the tableView's data source.
总结是，你设置了tableView的数据源。
That's automatic if you're using UITableViewController.
这是自动的，如果你使用UITableViewController。
You implement numberOfSections and numberOfRowsInSection.
您实现numberofsection和numberOfRowsInSection。
And then you implement cellForRowAt.
然后你实现cellForRowAt。
And give back a tableView cell,
然后返回一个tableView单元格，
either a custom subclass if you're doing custom,
任意一个自定义子类，
or just setting the detailed text label and
或者只是设置详细的文本标签
then the normal text label if you're not, question?
如果不是的话，普通的文本标签，问题?
Okay, so the question is, what do I answer for
问题是，我要怎么回答
that number of sections thing if, over time,
如果，随着时间的推移，
my tableView is growing, right?
我的tableView在增长，对吧?
Maybe data is coming in from the network, or
也许数据来自网络，或者
the user is clicking on things that makes more table happen.
用户正在点击使更多表发生的事情。
You can answer it that differently in any time, but
你可以在任何时候以不同的方式回答这个问题
what you're basically saying is, what if my model changes?
你基本上说的是，如果我的模型改变了怎么办?
I need my UI, right, to keep up with it.
我需要我的UI，来跟上它。
If my model gets bigger, then I need more rows.
如果我的模型变大，那么我需要更多的行。
Well, you're gonna see that it's really important to,
你会发现这很重要，
every time your model changes,
每次你的模型改变，
you need to tell the tableView about it.
你需要告诉tableView。
And you're gonna tell it things like
你会告诉它类似的事情
I've added a new section.
我添加了一个新的部分。
And then it will come back and
然后它会回来
ask you all these questions again, all right.
再问你所有这些问题。
So, that's how it works.
这就是它的工作原理。
It might come back and ask you these questions including
它可能会回来问你这些问题，包括
cellForRowAt over and over and over.
cellForRowAt一遍又一遍。
As you tell it that you've changed your model.
当你告诉它你改变了你的模型。
But of course, your model can change over time.
当然，你的模型会随着时间而改变。
By the way, the titles of the sections,
顺便说一下，这些章节的标题，
remember when I showed you the countries and it had Japan and
还记得我指给你们看的国家，还有日本
Mexico as titles.
墨西哥的标题。
Those are considered part of the data.
这些被认为是数据的一部分。
So, those are part of the UITableViewDataSource
这些是UITableViewDataSource的一部分
protocol as well.
协议。
This method title for header or footer in section, and
该方法标题为页眉或页脚，以及
you pass the section number and it gives you the thing.
你通过了section号，它就给你了。
You can also do it with a view, using the delegate.
您还可以使用委托进行视图操作。
But if you want to just do it as a string,
但如果你想把它作为一个字符串来做，
you'd use the data source.
您将使用数据源。
There's a lot of other methods in the protocol.
协议中还有很多其他的方法。
I'm not gonna really talk about them,
我就不讲了，
they have to do with things like deleting rows or
它们与删除行或者
rearranging the rows, things like that.
重新排列行，像这样。
If your model allows those things to happen,
如果你的模型允许这些事情发生，
like things being deleted.
喜欢东西被删除了。
Then you're gonna have to teach yourself this.
那你就得自学这一点。
Most of you will probably end up doing this for
你们中的大多数很可能会这样做
your final project.
你的最终项目。
I'm not gonna ask you to do it in the homework, but
我不会要求你们在作业里做，但是
you'll probably do it for your final project.
你可能会为你的期末项目做这件事。
It's extra credit in the homework,
这是额外的学分，
if you wanna get a head start on that.
如果你想从头开始。
All right let's talk about seguing from a row.
好，我们来讨论一下segue。
So I've got a row there, okay,
这里有一行，
this one actually has a detail disclosure in there as well.
这个实际上也有一个细节信息。
And I wanna segue out of that thing, how do I do that?
我想从这个问题中退出，我该怎么做呢?
Very simple,
很简单,
I do it just like any other segueing from the button.
我就像其他从按钮上segue的segue一样。
I'm just gonna Ctrl+drag from the row to the MVC I want to
我将Ctrl +拖动到我想要的MVC
segue to.
segue。
And it's going to put up this black window.
它会把这个黑色的窗口挂起来。
Now, this black window
现在,这个黑色的窗口
is a little different than other segues.
与其他segue有一点不同。
Because you see it has two sections, Selection Segue and
因为你看到它有两个部分，选择Segue和
Accessory Action, okay?
辅助动作,好吗?
So the Selection Segue is if they click on the row and
选择Segue是如果他们点击行
the Accessory Action is if they click on
附属动作是如果他们点击
the little accessory button.
小附件按钮。
But it's just a normal segue, once you create the segue,
但这只是一个普通的segue，一旦你创建了segue，
you can click on it and inspect it.
你可以点击它并检查它。
Just like any other segue,
和其他segue一样，
you can set its identifier up there to something.
你可以将它的标识符设置为某个东西。
And then you're gonna have prepare for segue.
然后你要准备segue。
So, here I've set the identifier to be AbcSegue.
这里我将标识符设为AbcSegue。
So lets take a look at what prepare for
让我们来看看准备什么
segue looks like when you're doing this kinda segue.
segue看起来就像你在做这个segue的时候。
It looks almost exactly the same,
看起来几乎是一样的，
here I've got a prepare for segue.
这里我有一个prepareforsegue。
I've noticed that the sender there is Any.
我注意到发件人有。
And when you're segueing into tableView,
当你segue到tableView时，
what do you think that Any is gonna be?
你觉得会怎么样?
UITableViewCell, okay, that view that contains the row.
UITableViewCell，好的，这个视图包含行。
So that is going to be the sender.
这就是sender。
Just like a button is the sender
就像一个按钮是发送者
if you click on a button to segue, the row,
如果你点击一个按钮来segue，这一行，
the UITableViewCell, is the sender in that case.
UITableViewCell是这种情况下的sender。
So the first thing you're gonna wanna
所以你要做的第一件事
do is convert the sender to a TableViewCell.
do是将发送者转换为TableViewCell。
And specifically to your subclass or table view cell.
具体到你的子类或表视图单元格。
If you have a custom cell in case you wanna
如果你有一个定制的单元格，以防你想要
do anything that's specific to your TableView cell.
对您的TableView单元格做任何特定的操作。
If not then you can just do it to UITableViewCell.
如果不是这样的话，你可以把它做UITableViewCell。
And then you wanna get the index path of that cell so
然后你想要得到那个单元格的索引路径
that you know what row where you're segueing from.
你知道你在什么地方segue。
Because every row, you can click on it, it will segue.
因为每一行，你可以点击它，它就会segue。
So, you need to know which row.
你需要知道哪一行。
And you do that by
你这样做
And you can't pass any to that, you have to pass
你不能错过任何一个，你必须通过
UITableViewCell or subclass thereof, indexPath(for: cell).
UITableViewCell或其子类，indexPath(for:cell)。
Now, I'm gonna give you one of those index path
现在，我要给你一条索引路径
things remember?
的事情还记得吗?
and row.
和行。
Then, you're gonna get your seguedToMVC as usual.
然后，你会像往常一样得到你的seguedToMVC。
And you're going to prepare your Segue to public API, and
你会准备好Segue到公共API
you're going to do it using the data in your model based
你将使用基于模型的数据
on the section and row that was clicked on.
在被点击的部分和行上。
Got it?
明白了吗?
So pretty easy segue from it.
很容易从它segue。
So yes you're gonna use your public API of your
是的，你会使用你的公共API
segue to MVC.
segue MVC。
What about the table view's delegate?
表视图的委托呢?
We talked about the data
我们讨论了数据
source; what about the table view's delegate?
源;表视图的委托呢?
It's got a kind of a miscellaneous
它有一种杂项
bunch of stuff in there but generally the delegate
里面有很多东西但通常是委托
is talking about how the table view is displayed, and
正在讨论如何显示表视图，以及
the data source is what data is actually in the table.
数据源是表中实际的数据。
Okay so that's the difference.
这就是区别。
So the delegate we're talking about things,
所以我们讨论的委托，
yeah they're usually the same object.
是的，它们通常是同一个物体。
So the delegate also has all the will, did, should things.
因此，委托也有所有的意愿。
That you could watch what's happening in the table view.
可以看到表视图中发生了什么。
This row did get selected, things like that.
这一行确实被选中了，像这样。
For example, here's table view target action, so
例如，这里的表视图目标操作
if when you click on a row, if you don't want a segue, but
如果你点击一行，如果你不想要segue，但是
you just want to be target action like a button,
你只需要像一个按钮那样做目标动作，
well you can't really do that.
你不能这么做。
You can't do target action because a row is not
你不能做目标动作，因为一行不是
a UIButton.
UIButton。
But you can implement this delegate method tableView
但你可以实现这个委托方法tableView
didSelectRowAt indexPath.
didSelectRowAt indexPath。
And when someone touches on that row,
当有人触摸这一行，
this is gonna get called.
这将会被调用。
So, it's just like target action right.
这就像目标行为。
It told you what happened.
它告诉你发生了什么。
So, now you can look at the index path row in section to
现在你可以看一下section中的索引路径行
know which row was selected so we call that target action.
知道选择哪一行，所以我们称之为目标动作。
You did the same thing with that detail
你对这个细节做了同样的事情
disclosure by the way.
信息披露。
So I'm gonna click on the detail disclosure we're gonna
我要点击我们要讲的细节信息
get this method in your delegate called
在您的委托中调用该方法
accessoryButtonTappedForRow- With indexPath.
accessoryButtonTappedForRow——indexPath。
Okay, so now you know which row is that.
现在你知道哪一行了。
So when things are clicked on, you can use segue or
当你点击的时候，你可以使用segue
you can use these to find out things were clicked on and
你可以用这些来发现被点击的东西
do whatever you want.
做任何你想要的。
So yeah, a lot of wills and dids and all those things.
所以，是的，很多遗嘱，dids和所有这些东西。
You can look at the documentation for
您可以查看文档
UITableViewDelegate.
UITableViewDelegate。
Now back to what this guy was asking before.
回到这个问题之前。
What happens if my model changes?
如果我的模型改变了会发生什么?
It gets bigger?
它变大吗?
Or even gets smaller or whatever?
或者变得更小?
One thing you can do that's kind of a hammer is
有一件事你可以做，那就是锤子
reloadData.
reloadData。
If you go reloadData on your table view it's going to call
如果你将reloadData放在你的表视图上它会调用
all of your data source methods again.
所有的数据源方法。
How many sections you got, how many rows in each section?
你有多少个section，每个section中有多少行?
Give me a cell for every single visible row.
给每一个可见的行给我一个单元格。
You see what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗?
It's going to do the whole thing all over again.
它将会从头再做一遍。
It's kind of a hammer because if you know that you only
这有点像锤子，因为如果你只知道你
changed one section okay?
改变一段好吗?
Then you can call something like reloadRows (at
然后您可以调用reloadRows(at)
indexPaths...).
indexPaths……)。
And indexPaths would tell the sections and rows.
索引路径会告诉各部分和行。
With some animation.
一些动画。
And animations can be like fade in or
动画也可以像褪色一样
slide from the bottom or things like that.
从底部滑动。
So there are lighter weight ones you can call.
所以重量更轻。
And I'm actually gonna show you in the demo,
我将在demo中展示给大家，
we're gonna call one where we're just gonna tell
我们把它叫做，我们要告诉它的地方
the table view that we inserted a section and
我们插入一个部分和
it's going to immediately just ask me
它马上就会问我
the data source message about that section and nothing else.
关于该部分的数据源消息和其他内容。
So you do need to tell the table view
所以需要告诉表视图
every time you change your model.
每次你改变你的模型。
If you change your model in
如果你改变模型
any way that would change the number of sections and rows.
任何可以改变section和行的数目的方法。
Or even the display of a row,
甚至是一行的显示，
you need to tell the table view.
您需要告诉表视图。
So, just always think about that when you're
所以，当你在做的时候，总是想一下
writing table view code.
写表格视图代码。
Change my model, tell the table view.
更改我的模型，告诉表视图。
Right away.
马上。
You want to tell the table view right away.
您需要立即告诉表视图。
And change your model first, then change your table view.
首先改变你的模型，然后改变你的表格视图。
Because when you tell your table view
因为当你告诉你的表格视图
things have changed, it's gonna go back and ask you, so
事情发生了变化，它会回去问你
for IndexPath, number of sections,
对于IndexPath，分段数，
it'll ask you those questions, some of them again.
它会问你这些问题，一些问题。
So make sure your models are already changed and
所以要确保你的模型已经改变了
ready to answer those questions.
准备好回答这些问题。
Le's talk about the height of rows.
我们来讨论一下行的高度。
The height of the row
的高度
generally set in the Storyboard.
通常在故事板中设置。
So you could resize it and set it and tha's what it is but
你可以调整它的大小并设置它，但是
you can also ask the delegate.
你也可以问代表。
You can also implement a method in the delegate and
您还可以在委托中实现方法
it'll ask the delegate, what height should this row be?
它会问委托，这一行的高度是多少?
This might be very useful in your homework, by the way.
顺便说一下，这可能对你的家庭作业很有用。
But this is for when you have
但这是当你拥有的时候
the rows that change height in some calculated way.
以某种计算方式改变高度的行。
Maybe you have an image in there, and
也许你在里面有一个图像
it's got different aspect ratios, for example.
例如，它有不同的方面比率。
And so it's different heights sometimes, whatever.
所以有时会有不同的高度。
So you can answer it this way.
所以你可以这样回答。
Of course, the other way you can control the height
当然，另一种方法是控制高度
is by doing auto layout, and
是通过自动布局吗
setting your height to be automatic dimension.
设定高度为自动尺寸。
If you set your height to be UITableViewAutomaticDimension,
如果你设置你的身高UITableViewAutomaticDimension,
that means go figure it out from the auto layout please.
这意味着你得从自动布局中找出答案。
So those are the three was you can set the height.
这三个就是你可以设置高度。
Set it fixed in the story board, answer this delegate
把它固定在故事板上，回答这个委托
method here, heightForRowAt indexPath,
方法在这里,heightForRowAt indexPath,
or set it to the automatic dimension.
或者将其设置为自动维度。
If you do the automatic ways then you also probably want to
如果你用自动的方法，那么你也可能想要
set the estimated row height.
设置估计的行高度。
That just tells the table view calculate from auto layout but
这只是告诉表视图从自动布局计算
for all those cells the 100,000 cells that aren't
对所有这些细胞来说，10万个细胞不是
on screen please don't do auto layout for 100,000 cells.
在屏幕上，请不要为100,000个单元的自动布局。
Just estimate them to be about this and as they start to come
只要估计一下他们的情况，就在他们开始的时候
on screen then it's gonna do the auto layout and
在屏幕上，它会自动布局
pick the exact right height okay.
选择正确的高度。
So that's why you need to estimate.
这就是你需要估算的原因。
And there's also a delicate method,
还有一种微妙的方法，
estimated height per row at whatever.
估计每一行的高度。
So there's dozens of methods also, in table view itself.
在表视图中也有很多方法。
Not in its delegates, but in table view itself.
不是在它的委托中，而是在表视图本身。
You can scroll to a row cuz it's a scroll view.
你可以滚动到一行，因为它是一个滚动视图。
It knows how to do scrolling.
它知道如何滚动。
You can control the look, the separators between rows.
你可以控制看，行之间的分隔符。
All those kind of things.
诸如此类的事情。
So you're definitely want to familiarize yourself
所以你肯定想要熟悉自己
with the table view API itself.
使用表视图API本身。
Don't forget about that.
不要忘记这一点。
All right, so I'm not coming back to this slide.
好了，我不会再回到幻灯片上了。
So just give you a quick coming up here.
所以给你们一个快速的来到这里。
We have collection view on Friday.
我们周五有收集视图。
So collection view is very similar to table view,
集合视图和表格视图非常相似，
but the layout doesn't have to be in a strict table.
但是布局并不一定要在严格的表中。
It can be kind of laid out any way you want.
它可以是你想要的任何方式。
But it's the same kind of thing where there's data and
但这和数据是一样的
it's gonna ask you how many sections there, how many row,
它会问你有多少个section，有多少行，
not rows but items in that section, then it's gonna have
不是行，而是这个部分的项，然后它就有了
this little extra mechanism for doing a lay out.
这个额外的作用机制。
So it's really awesome.
这真是太棒了。
I'd love to have time to teach it in lecture not in
我很想有时间在课堂上教它
the optional section but I've got so much to teach in this
可选的部分，但我有很多东西要教
course and you really need to understand TableView first,
当然，你需要先理解TableView，
which is a little simpler, before you can move onto
在你继续之前，这有一点简单吗
CollectionView- but really don't miss Friday.
收集视图-但实际上不要错过星期五。
It will be a good way to really it much more powerful
这将是一个很好的方法，让它更强大
kind of data presentation UI.
一种数据演示UI。
And then next week we gonna talk about Core Data,
下周我们要讲Core Data，
which is the object-oriented database in iOS,
这是iOS中面向对象的数据库，
really powerful mechanism.
真正强大的机制。
Right now, I'm gonna be doing a big demo that shows
现在，我要做一个大的演示
how to do all this TableView stuff and
如何处理这些TableView呢
also TextField and some other things.
还有TextField和其他一些东西。
And your Assignment 4 is out,
作业4已经出来了，
and it's due in one week, on Wednesday and it's
这是在周三，周三
basically to take what I do today and build a better one.
基本上就是拿我今天做的，做一个更好的。
More feature-full.
更多的feature-full。
So that's why you
这就是为什么你
always want to understand what I'm doing in lecture, because
总是想知道我在课堂上做了什么，因为
I'm almost always just asking you to do the same thing.
我几乎总是要求你做同样的事情。
Okay so I'm gonna build a completely
好的，我将建立一个完整的
fresh app from scratch.
新的应用程序从头开始。
Like I said before it's gonna be a Twitter client.
就像我之前说的，它会成为Twitter的客户。
We're gonna be doing Twitter searches.
我们会在Twitter上搜索。
It's gonna be a single view app.
它将是一个单一的视图应用。
i'm gonna call it Smashtag, kind of like hashtag.
我把它命名为Smashtag，类似于hashtag。
As always,
像往常一样,
This is gonna be an iPhone-only app.
这将是一个iphone应用程序。
And that's true for your homework as well.
这也适用于你们的作业。
Okay, iPhone-only, we're not gonna do an iPad thing.
好的，iphone，我们不会做iPad的事。
You already learned that with assignment three.
你们已经学过作业3了。
Trying to keep what you're learning
努力保持你所学的
as new as possible with each one.
每个人都有新的可能。
I'm gonna put this where I always put everything.
我要把所有东西都放进去。
Here we go, I'm gonna get rid of some of these things over
现在，我要把这些东西去掉
here that we don't really use very much.
这里我们不太用。
Actually I'm gonna leave plist as you'll see.
实际上，我将留下plist。
New group, we'll do Supporting Files here, and
新的组，我们将在这里做支持文件
I will move that down.
我把它移下来。
Now I'm gonna start by taking my Storyboard here and
现在我要从我的故事板开始
just totally wiping it out.
把它擦掉。
Okay, I'm just gonna take the one controller that I got,
我要用我得到的一个控制器，
the free one, and just delete it.
免费的，然后删除它。
I'm even gonna go over to this code right here and
我还要讲一下这里的代码
delete that, same thing I did in the last demo.
删除它，和我在上次demo中做的一样。
Cuz I don't need any of that,
因为我不需要这些，
I'm gonna start from scratch here.
从这里开始。
So, we're building a table view app, so
我们正在构建一个表格视图应用程序
let's grab a table view, I'm gonna scroll down here.
让我们抓取一个表格视图，我将向下滚动这里。
Here's a table view right here, I just drag it out.
这里有一个表格视图，我把它拖出来。
Now this table view if we wanna use it as a delegate and
现在这个表格视图，如果我们想把它用作委托
data source, or if we wanna have outlets to it, we,
数据源，或者如果我们想要outlet到它，
of course, need a subclass of it.
当然，需要一个子类。
So let's go ahead and do that, New > File, okay.
我们继续，新建>文件。
It's gonna be a Cocoa Touch subclass,
它将是一个Cocoa触摸子类，
namely a UITableViewController.
即UITableViewController。
And I'm gonna call this my TweetTableViewController,
我将称之为TweetTableViewController,
because it's gonna show tweets.
因为它会显示推文。
All right, and I'm gonna be very careful to put it here,
好的，我要非常小心地把它放在这里，
not at the top level of my project there.
不是在我的项目的顶层。
And here we go, here's our code right here.
这是我们的代码。
I'm gonna delete this View Controller Lifecycle
我要删除这个视图控制器生命周期
stuff, as usual.
东西,像往常一样。
But you'll notice the TableViewController
但你会注意到TableViewController
also has some extra stuff.
还有一些额外的东西。
You recognize those methods, numberOfSections, okay,
你能认出这些方法，numberofsection，好的，
numberOfRowsInSection, and cellForRowAt indexPath.
numberOfRowsInSection,也和cellForRowAt indexPath。
These are the key UITableViewDataSource
这些是关键的UITableViewDataSource
methods here.
这里的方法。
Now there's some other UITableViewDataSource
现在还有其他UITableViewDataSource
methods here as well, these are for
这里的方法也是
things like deleting rows, moving rows.
比如删除行，移动行。
So when you're doing your extra credit, or
所以当你在做额外的贷款时
when you're doing your final project,
当你做最后的项目时，
you'll be wanting to not delete those.
你会希望不删除那些。
But I will delete those just to make our code a little bit
但是我将删除这些，只是为了让我们的代码更简单一些
cleaner here.
清洁。
So that's our UITableViewController
这就是我们UITableViewController
subclass, we'll have to implement these in a second.
子类，我们必须在一秒钟内实现这些。
But let's go back to our Storyboard.
让我们回到故事板。
We also obviously wanna set our identity here to instead
我们显然也想把我们的身份设置成这样
of being just generic UITableViewController,
作为一个通用的UITableViewController，
we want it to be a TweetTableViewController.
我们希望它是一个TweetTableViewController。
Also, where's our arrow coming in?
还有，我们的箭头呢?
There's no arrow, so let's select it again and
没有箭头，我们再选一次
go back to attributes and pick is initial view controller, so
回到属性，选择是初始视图控制器
we get this arrow coming in.
我们得到这个箭头。
Okay, otherwise, when we launch our app,
好的，否则，当我们启动app时，
it's not gonna know what MVC to start with, all right?
它不知道从哪个MVC开始?
Now whenever we have a new MVC,
现在每当我们有一个新的MVC，
what's one of the first things we always wanna do?
我们想做的第一件事是什么?
Define its model.
定义它的模型。
Understand what this MVC is all about.
了解这个MVC的含义。
What does it show or do?
它展示了什么或做了什么?
And I'm going to pick my model to be an array of tweets.
我将把我的模型选为一条推文数组。
Okay, I'm gonna call it tweets.
我把它命名为tweets。
But I'm actually gonna make it be an array
但我要把它变成一个数组
of array of tweets.
数组的tweet。
Okay, why am I making an array of an array of tweets?
为什么我要创建一系列的tweet呢?
Because I'm going to be able to put some tweets in my table
因为我将能够在我的表中放置一些tweet
and then go fetch some more and put more in.
然后再去拿一些，再放进去。
And every time I put more in, I'm gonna put it as a new
每次我投入更多，我就把它作为一个新的
section, okay, table view section.
section，好的，表格视图部分。
So each array on the inside of this array
数组内部的每个数组
is another batch of tweets.
是另一批推文。
And the outer array is all of my sections.
外数组是所有的部分。
So I have a really nice data structure here.
这里有一个很好的数据结构。
It really matches up nicely with table view.
它与表视图非常匹配。
And it's kind of nice to have that kind of data structure.
这种数据结构很好。
And I kind of recommend that in the homework if you can
如果可以的话，我推荐你们做作业
make your data structure match up with sections and
使您的数据结构与各个部分相匹配
rows, then it makes the implementation
行，然后进行实现
of all these methods down here a lot simpler.
在所有这些方法中，简单多了。
All right, so, I've got another part of my model,
好了，我还有另一个模型，
though, which is some searchText.
不过，这是一些搜索文本。
So the searchText is like #stanford,
所以searchText就像#斯坦福，
that's what I wanna search for.
这就是我想要搜索的。
So this searchText is what I'm searching for
所以这个搜索文本就是我正在寻找的
to find my tweets.
找到我的微博。
And I'm making this one public,
我把这个公布于众，
this is gonna be a public part of my model.
这将是我模型的公共部分。
So anyone using my MVC, they set the search text.
任何人使用我的MVC，他们都设置了搜索文本。
I will show those tweets.
我会展示那些推文。
That's what I do.
这就是我做的。
All right, and I'm gonna do that by populating this part
我要通过填充这个部分来实现
of my model over here to show them.
我在这里展示的模型。
So what do I need to do if the searchText is set?
如果搜索文本设置为，我需要做什么?
So I need to do some didSet here, so the public model,
所以我需要在这里做一些didSet，公共模型，
if something sets it, I have to react well to it.
如果有什么事情发生，我必须对它做出反应。
I mean, one thing that I'm gonna wanna do is remove
我的意思是，我要做的一件事是删除
all the tweets that are already in my table.
所有的推文都在我的表格里。
And when I remove those from my model up here,
当我从模型中移除这些，
I need to tell the table view about it.
我需要告诉表视图。
So I'm gonna have the tableView.reloadData(), which
我将有tableview。reloaddata()，它
is the hammer, which is okay, because I removed everything,
是锤子，没关系，因为我把所有东西都拿走了，
so the hammer's gonna be pretty light,
所以锤子会很轻，
a little ball-peen hammer.
一个小榔头。
Okay, just going to clear the table out, so
好吧，把桌子清理干净
tha's perfectly fine in this case.
在这种情况下，他完全没问题。
What else do I need to do?
我还需要做什么?
Well, I, now I need to search for tweets.
我现在需要搜索推文。
So I have to write a function to do that to search for
所以我要写一个函数来搜索
some tweet.
一些推特。
I'm also gonna set my title equal to the searchText.
我也要设置我的标题与searchText相等。
That way if I happen to be in a navigation controller or
如果我碰巧在导航控制器中
something like that, it'll show whatever I'm searching
像这样，它会显示我搜索的内容
for, #stanford or whatever at the top, so
比如，# stanford或者其他的
I'll just make my UI look nice there.
我让UI看起来不错。
All right, so
好吧,那么
we got to do this private func searchForTweets.
我们要做这个私人的func searchForTweets。
Okay, so this is the thing that needs to go off and
这就是需要关闭的东西
find these tweets, and so we'll do that in a moment.
找到这些推文，我们马上就做。
One thing I'm also gonna do is I'm gonna do viewDidLoad,
我还要做的一件事是viewDidLoad，
just for testing purposes.
只是为了测试目的。
You notice I do this a lot when I'm developing, and
你注意到我在开发过程中经常这样做
I wanna have some testing,
我想要测试一下，
I'm gonna just set my model to something.
我要把模型设置成什么。
So we'll do #stanford, okay, just for testing.
所以我们会做# stanford，好的，只是为了测试。
Once we're got our MVC working,
一旦我们有了MVC，
its public API is working, then we will remove this code.
它的公共API正在工作，然后我们将删除这段代码。
It's just testing code.
这只是测试代码。
Okay, now, we have an error here.
现在我们有一个错误。
And this error is Swift saying excuse me.
这个错误是斯威夫特说抱歉。
What is tweet?
推特是什么?
What is that type?
那是什么类型?
And I didn't really want you to be wasting your time in
我并不想让你浪费你的时间
your homework figuring out how to go fetch
你的家庭作业弄清楚怎么去取
a tweet from Twitter and do a request and all that.
推特上的一条推文，做了一个请求。
So I wrote a framework that did it for you.
所以我给你们写了一个框架。
And by framework, I mean a framework like this.
通过框架，我指的是这样一个框架。
Like UIKit, right, UIKit is this like library of a whole
就像UIKit一样，UIKit就像一个整体的库
bunch of data structures that you can use to build your app.
可以用来构建应用程序的数据结构。
Well, I wrote one for you that will do Twitter stuff for it.
我为你写了一个，为它做推特。
And it has something in it called tweet.
它有一个叫做tweet的东西。
And it also has something called request that lets
它还有一个叫request的东西
you make a Twitter request.
你提出了一个Twitter请求。
All right, so that thing is right over here.
好了，这个就在这里。
Now, how do frameworks work?
那么，框架是如何工作的呢?
How do you use them when they're not built into
当它们不是内置的时候，你如何使用它们
the system like Apple?
系统像苹果?
And the answer is, you need to build a higher level structure
答案是，你需要建立一个更高层次的结构
for Xcode to work with called a workspace.
对于Xcode来说，使用一个工作空间。
So I'm actually gonna close this project.
所以我要关闭这个项目。
I'm closing this project.
我关闭这个项目。
And I'm going to Xcode, and I'm gonna create a new thing,
我要去Xcode，创建一个新东西，
which you've never seen before, called a workspace.
这是你以前从未见过的，叫做工作空间。
Now when I create this workspace,
现在当我创建这个工作区时，
it wants to know where to put it.
它想知道把它放在哪里。
Be careful here, look,
小心这里,看,
it's trying to put it inside my Smashtag project,
它试图把它放到我的Smashtag项目中，
which I don't wanna do that.
我不想这么做。
I wanna put it up the top of my Developer level here,
我想把它放在Developer水平的顶端，
same place I put all of my projects, okay,
我把所有的项目都放在同一个地方，
so really be careful about that.
所以要小心。
So I'm gonna call this L9, this is lecture 9, so
我把它叫做L9，这是第九讲
we'll call it L9.
我们把它叫做L9。
And I hit Save, and this created this workspace.
我点击了Save，这创建了这个工作区。
But notice in the navigator, there's nothing there.
但注意在导航器中，这里什么都没有。
So what do we put in a workspace?
那么我们把什么放在工作空间里呢?
Well, what we put in a workspace are other projects.
我们在工作空间中放入的是其他项目。
And this workspace is just gonna collect all those
这个工作区会收集所有这些
projects, because they kind of go together.
项目，因为它们在一起。
And obviously, this Twitter framework that I'm providing
显然，我提供的这个Twitter框架
to you right here goes together with Smashtag,
在这里你和Smashtag一起，
which is this thing we've been working on so far.
这就是我们一直在研究的东西。
Now what you drag down in here is the .xcodeproj,
现在你往下拉的是。xcodeproj，
because it's the project itself that you wanna put in
因为这是你想要投入的项目本身
this workspace.
这个工作区。
So you just drag that in for both of them, so
所以你只需要把它们拖进来
I'm gonna open this one as well.
我也要打开这个。
Here's the Xcode project for this Twitter thing.
这是这个Twitter的Xcode项目。
Drag in, now be careful not to put it inside,
拉进去，小心不要把它放进里面，
see how that's trying to put it inside Smashtag there?
看到怎么把它放进Smashtag里面了吗?
Put it outside, so that they're siblings.
把它放在外面，这样他们是兄弟姐妹。
Now I have this workspace right here that has two
现在这个工作区有两个
projects in it, and you even go here and hide others.
在里面的项目，你甚至会在这里隐藏别人。
And if we look in the Smashtag one, woo, looks familiar.
如果我们看一下Smashtag 1，哇，看起来很熟悉。
This is the code we were just working on, right?
这就是我们正在研究的代码，对吧?
If we look in the Twitter one,
如果我们看看推特，
this is the code I am providing you.
这是我给你的代码。
Now, what's in here?
现在,在这里是什么?
Here's tweet which is this struct and
这是推特，它是这个结构
it's got all the things you would expect in a tweet.
它有你在推特上期待的所有东西。
The text of the tweet, the user who created it,
这条推文的文本，创建它的用户，
which is another thing, user right here,
这是另一件事，这里的用户，
and the user has a screen name that's at sign something,
用户有一个屏幕上的名字，
the actual name, a unique identifier for the user.
实际的名称，用户的唯一标识符。
Back to tweet, it's also got a unique identifier.
回到tweet，它也有一个唯一的标识符。
It's also got things that are embedded in the tweet like
它也有嵌入在推特上的东西
other hashtags and
其他标签和
other users that are referenced inside the tweet.
在tweet中引用的其他用户。
And even media cuz you know a lot of times
甚至是媒体，你知道很多次
tweets have an image with them too.
推文也有自己的形象。
And the other thing that's of importance in this Twitter
还有一件事在Twitter上很重要
framework that I'm giving you is this class Request,
我给你们的框架是这个类请求，
Twitter Request right here.
Twitter的请求。
And this Request class is the thing you use to make requests
这个请求类是用来生成请求的
for Twitter.
对于Twitter。
Now, you don't need to look at any of the implementation
现在，您不需要查看任何实现
of any of this, and in fact, you can go and
这其中的任何一个，事实上，你可以去
do assistant editor.
做助理编辑。
And if you do assistant editor on something like this,
如果你做这样的助理编辑，
you're actually gonna see its public API here.
你会看到它的公共API。
See all those public, public public, public,
看到所有公众，公众，公众，
public; now we have not seen this public keyword before,
公众的;我们之前没见过这个公共关键字，
all we've seen is private or fileprivate.
我们看到的都是私有或文件私有。
So what does this public thing mean?
那么这个公共事物意味着什么呢?
Look, I put public in all this these things over here.
看，我把这些东西都公开了。
Public means that not only is it not private but
公开的意思是它不仅不是私有的，而是
you can see it even if this framework is being used by
即使这个框架被使用，你也能看到它
some other project.
一些其他的项目。
So public means public outside of this framework, right,
所以公众的意思是在这个框架之外，
make sense?
有意义吗?
So in UIKit a lot of things are marked public.
在UIKit中很多东西都是公开的。
All the things you can use have to be marked public cuz
你可以使用的所有东西都必须标记为公共的cuz
it's in a different framework than your app.
它与你的应用程序不同。
Your app is kind of a framework, in a sense, so
在某种意义上，你的应用是一个框架
that's public.
这是公开的。
And then, also notice farther down,
然后，再往下看，
these methods are marked internal; that means I can
这些方法都有内部标记;这意味着我可以
only use them inside my framework, so I can't call any
只在我的框架内使用它们，所以我不能调用任何
of these methods from Smashtag, they're internal.
这些方法来自Smashtag，它们是内部的。
This actually, you haven't seen this keyword because
实际上，你还没见过这个关键字
it's the default, all the methods you've ever created
它是默认的，所有你创建的方法
that you didn't mark private or fileprivate are internal.
您没有标记私有或fileprivate是内部的。
It's the default, so
这是默认的,所以
you haven't put the word internal there, okay.
你还没有把这个词放在里面。
So, let's look at the public API.
那么，让我们看看公共API。
Let's not even pay any attention to that, and
让我们甚至不去关注它
look at the public API.
看看公共API。
This public API of Request, for making requests,
请求的公共API，用于提出请求，
we're only going to use three things.
我们只会用三样东西。
One is this convenience initializer
一个是这个方便的初始化程序
where you just give it something to search for and
你给它找什么
how many results you want.
你想要多少结果。
And then this method fetchTweets where you just
然后这个方法会在你刚才的地方获取信息
give it this closure which it will call when it's done.
给它关闭它会在完成后调用它。
It's gonna go off and do it on another thread and
它会在另一个线程上执行
when it's done it will call.
当它完成时，它会调用。
And that's going to have an array of the tweets it found
它会有一个它找到的推文数组
that match your search.
匹配你的搜索。
what we're gonna use is this one down here, newer where if
我们要用的就是这个，更新的地方，如果
And then last,
然后,最后
you ask it a request, give me a newer request.
你问它一个请求，给我一个新的请求。
It'll give your request that you can use to get newer
它会给你的请求，你可以用来更新
tweets.
tweet。
Tweets that have been tweeted after
之后推特发推
the previous one that you've got.
之前的一个。
So, that's all we're gonna use here.
这就是我们要用到的。
We're not really gonna use any of the other API
我们不会使用其他的API
in this request.
在这个请求。
In your homework, you'll have to know this API here of
在你们的作业中，你们需要知道这个API
Tweet cause you'll have to be able to get the text and
推特，因为你必须能够得到文本和
the user information and also MediaItems so
用户信息和MediaItems
you can get the URLs of images that are in there, etc.
你可以得到图像的url，等等。
But you never have to look at the private implementation of
但你从来不用看它的私有实现
this framework so don't even waste your time looking there.
这个框架甚至不会浪费你的时间去看那里。
Just look at things marked public,
看看那些有标记的公共事物，
there's not a lot of things marked public- that's the only
没有很多东西是公开的，只有这样
thing you're going to look for.
你要找的东西。
Now how do I use this framework,
如何使用这个框架呢?
this Twitter framework in Smashtag?
这是Smashtag的Twitter框架?
Well, you have to do one step.
你需要做一步。
You can't just put them in the same workspace and
你不能只把它们放在同一个工作区中
start working.
开始工作。
Well, two steps, one is I need to say import Twitter.
有两个步骤，一个是，我需要输入Twitter。
Just like I say import UIKit, if I want to use this Twitter
就像我说的导入UIKit，如果我想使用这个Twitter
framework up here I have to say import Twitter.
在这里我必须输入Twitter。
That's gonna cause this tweet to start being
这将导致这条推文开始
recognized as a type because it's gonna see this
被认为是一种类型，因为它会看到这个
tweet type right over here.
推特类型在这里。
But the other important thing, don't forget,
但另一件重要的事，别忘了，
is you need to tell Xcode that when you build Smashtag that
您是否需要告诉Xcode当您构建Smashtag时
app includes Twitter in it.
应用程序包括Twitter。
And you do that by going to the Smashtag project, okay,
通过Smashtag项目，
the project settings.
项目设置。
And go all the way to the bottom where it says
然后一直走到底部
Embedded Binaries.
嵌入二进制文件。
And just pick up the product of your Twitter framework.
然后你就可以选择你的Twitter框架的产品。
You see where it says Products right here?
你看到这里的产品了吗?
Just pick that up and drag it in here, and that says,
把它拖到这里，然后说，
please put Twitter framework into my Smashtag,
请将Twitter框架放到我的Smashtag中，
because my Smashtag uses it.
因为我的Smashtag使用它。
If you don't do this step, then it'll all compile but
如果您不执行这个步骤，那么它将全部编译，但是
then when Smashtag runs, Twitter won't be there, and
然后当Smashtag运行时，Twitter不会在那里，而且
so it will fail.
所以它将会失败。
Now, I'm gonna make you do that step as part of
现在，我要让你做这一步
your homework.
你的家庭作业。
I will post this code for Smashtag, but
我将为Smashtag发布此代码，但是
I'm not gonna post the workspace, so
我不会发布工作空间
you're gonna have to build the workspace on your own.
你必须自己建一个工作区。
All right, so let's continue.
好，继续。
Now that we've got this array of tweets,
现在我们有了这一系列的推文，
what are we gonna do with this array of tweets?
我们要怎么处理这些推特?
Let's start by doing a fetch for our search text.
让我们开始为我们的搜索文本做一个取回。
So we got our search text,
我们得到了搜索文本，
we wanna go fetch all those things on there.
我们想去那里取回所有的东西。
That's what we're supposed to do in search for tweets.
这就是我们在搜索tweet时应该做的事情。
Let's make another function here,
我们来做另一个函数，
another little private func.
另一个小私有函数。
I'm gonna call it twitterRequest,
我把它叫做twitterRequest，
which is gonna return a Twitter.Request.
它会返回一个Twitter.Request。
But yeah, here's another thing.
但是，还有一件事。
This I can call tweet because I'm importing this Twitter
我可以调用tweet，因为我正在导入这个Twitter
framework and there's no other class called tweet, so
框架，没有其他的类叫做tweet，所以
i just have to call it tweet.
我只需要把它叫做tweet。
Its full name is actually Twitter.Tweet.
它的全名实际上是Twitter.Tweet。
Just like, you know, UITableViewController,
就像，UITableViewController，
it's full name is UIKit.UITableViewController.
它的全名是UIKit.UITableViewController。
use Twitter.Tweet because I think in Assignment 5, you
使用Twitter。推特，因为我认为在作业5中，你
Now i'm gonna
现在我要
might end up wanting to have you own local tweet class.
最后可能会想要拥有本地的tweet类。
So I'm gonna use Twitter.Tweet and
所以我要用Twitter。微博和
Twitter.Request everywhere but I wouldn't have to as long as
Twitter。请求无处不在，但我不需要那么长时间
I didn't have a class called Tweet or Request otherwise.
我没有一个叫Tweet或请求的类。
But this is a pretty generic name request so putting
但这是一个非常通用的名称请求
the Twitter dot on front might be kind of a good idea anyway.
不管怎样，在前面的Twitter上的点可能是个好主意。
All right so
好
the Twitter.Request function here is just going to return
Twitter。这里的请求函数将返回
a Twitter request that matches this search text.
与此搜索文本相匹配的Twitter请求。
And that's really, really simple,
这真的很简单，
I'm just gonna say, if I can let the query for
我只是想说，如果我能让查询出来
the search term equal the search text.
搜索项等于搜索文本。
And I wanna make sure that that query is not empty.
我要确保这个查询不是空的。
So I don't wanna search for nil or for the empty string.
我不想搜索nil或者空字符串。
So I'm just keeping that out of it right here.
我把它放在这里。
And otherwise I'm just gonna return a Twitter request using
否则我将返回一个使用的Twitter请求
that convenient initializer I told you about called Search.
那个方便的初始化器，我告诉过你叫搜索。
And I'm just gonna pass that query and,
我将通过这个查询，
well let's get 100 of them.
我们得到100个。
Okay, so we're gonna, we'll grab 100 tweets at a time.
我们会一次抓取100条tweet。
And if that's not true, if the search term is nil or
如果这不是真的，如果搜索项是nil
it's empty, then I'm gonna return nil from this.
它是空的，然后返回nil。
So let's make this be, you know, optional.
让我们把它变成可选的。
Okay, so everyone understand what this function does?
大家都明白这个函数的作用了吧?
It just makes a Twitter request that will search for
它只是发出了一个搜索的Twitter请求
our searchText, that's all it does.
我们的搜索文本，仅此而已。
So now down here in searchForTweets,
下面这里是searchForTweets，
I can say if I can let request equal the twitterRequest,
我可以说，如果我可以让请求等于twitterRequest，
which hopefully it can make.
希望它能做出来。
Okay, now I have a request.
好的，现在我有一个请求。
Now I just need to cause that request to happen.
现在我只需要让这个请求发生。
So I'm just gonna say this Twitter request.fetchTweets.
我只是想说这个推特请求。fetchtweets。
So this fetchTweets function right there, you see it?
fetchTweets函数在这里，你看到了吗?
The top one, okay,
上面的,
it takes this closure right here as an argument.
它把这个闭包作为一个参数。
I'm gonna double click on it, to show what it does here.
我要双击它，显示它在这里做什么。
I'm going to use trailing closure syntax to get rid of
我将使用尾随关闭语法来处理
the parentheses there.
那里的括号。
Now what's this?
现在这是什么?
This is the only argument in my closure.
这是我唯一的结论。
Those are the tweets that it fetched.
这些是它所获取的推文。
See it's an array of tweets.
看它是一条推文数组。
I'll call this newTweets.
我将称之为newTweets。
Okay, so that's going to be an array of tweets,
这将是一条推文数组，
I don't even need the parentheses here by the way.
我甚至不需要这个括号。
So I have newTweets.
所以我有newTweets。
So newTweets is gonna be an array of Tweet that it
所以newTweets将会是一个Tweet的数组
fetched; now, of course,
获取;现在,当然,
it's doing this off the main queue, right?
它是在主队列上执行的，对吧?
It's gotta go do that Twitter request,
它必须去做这个推特请求，
what if it's a really slow network?
如果网络真的很慢怎么办?
Or Twitter is really slow that time or whatever.
或者推特真的很慢。
I finally got these new tweets back, what do I wanna do?
我终于收到了这些新的推文，我想做什么?
So inside here,
所以在这里,
Well I just want to add them on to the end of my model,
我只是想把它们加到模型的末尾，
Here's my model, it's an array of array of tweets.
这是我的模型，它是一系列推文的数组。
right?
对吧?
Here's an array, so I'm just going to take my model, and
这是一个数组，我将用我的模型
append onto it this array of tweets.
在它上面添加这一系列的推文。
And actually, I'm not gonna append it on the end because
实际上，我不会把它追加到最后
I want all my new tweets to show up at the beginning,
我希望所有的新推文都能在一开始就出现，
so in section zero at the beginning, so
在第0节开始的时候
I'm gonna insert these new tweets at 0 in my array.
我将在数组中0插入这些新的tweet。
So right at the top.
在顶部。
So my new tweets are gonna come in at the top.
所以我的新推文将会出现在顶部。
Make sense?
有意义吗?
Now, we have an error there.
现在，我们有一个错误。
Can anyone guess why this error is here before I
有人知道为什么这个错误在我之前吗
open it?
打开它吗?
>> Mutating.
>> What? >> Yeah, mutating.
That's a good guess but no.
这是一个很好的猜测，但不是。
It's because self, it's the old closure cycle problem,
因为它是一个旧的闭合周期问题，
right?
对吧?
Since we're accessing self here,
既然我们在这里访问self，
these tweets as part of our self.
这些推文是我们自我的一部分。
We need to explicitly say that so
我们需要明确地说出来
that we can notice, we might have a memory cycle.
我们可以注意到，我们可能有一个记忆周期。
And do we have a memory cycle here?
这里有一个记忆周期吗?
In fact we do.
事实上,我们做的。
Because what if this view controller goes off to
因为如果这个视图控制器离开
fetch some tweets and it takes forever.
获取一些推文，这将花费永远。
And so the person says, I'll search for something else.
所以这个人说，我去找别的东西。
Now they said the search text is on the else and
现在他们说搜索文本在别的地方
another fetch goes off.
另一个拿了。
And now here comes the first fetch and it's irrelevant now
这是第一个取回，现在无关紧要了
because I already looked for something else.
因为我已经在寻找其他的东西。
So we do here, want to be careful to ignore
所以我们在这里做，要小心忽略
this when it comes back and we also, if someone searches and
当它回来的时候，我们也，如果有人搜索
it's taking forever and they hit back, we want our view
这是永远的，他们回击，我们想要我们的观点
controllers to be able to leave memory as well.
控制器也能留下记忆。
So we don't want the closure, the cycle here,
所以我们不希望这个循环，
we don't want this closure holding our self in memory.
我们不希望这个封闭在记忆中保持自我。
So we don't want this to be a strong pointer and
所以我们不希望它是一个强指针
we need to check to make sure that when we get back,
我们需要确认一下，当我们回来的时候，
it's still what we're interested in.
这仍然是我们感兴趣的。
So how can we break this cycle?
那么我们如何打破这个循环呢?
We're just gonna use our friend weak self, okay?
我们只是要用我们的朋友软弱的自己，好吗?
That's easy.
这很简单。
And that turns this into an optional.
这就变成了可选的。
So we added a question mark.
所以我们加了一个问号。
Boom, we broke that cycle.
繁荣，我们打破了这个循环。
So even if this fetch is sitting out there fetching,
因此，即使这个取回是坐在那里取回的，
it's not gonna be keeping our view controller in memory.
它不会把视图控制器保存在内存中。
Our view control can leave memory, and
我们的视图控制可以留下内存
if it comes back and
如果它回来了
it's gone, then this line of code will not execute.
它消失了，然后这行代码就不会执行了。
How about dealing with the fact that our request might
如何处理我们的请求可能的事实
have changed?
已经改变了吗?
Well, to do that,
嗯,要做到这一点,
I'm gonna have to keep track of our lastTwitterRequest,
我要跟踪我们的lastTwitterRequest，
actually we've got to put it inside here.
实际上我们要把它放在这里。
Okay, I'm gonna keep track of it, and
好吧，我要跟踪它，然后
then in here I'm not going to do this unless our
在这里，我不打算这么做，除非我们
request equals the lastTwitterRequest.
等于lastTwitterRequest请求。
So if this request that came back is not the last one we
所以如果这个请求返回不是最后一个
issued, then I'm not gonna do it.
发布，然后我就不做了。
And so let me go up here and
往上看
say private var lastTwitterRequest and
表示私有var lastTwitterRequest
that's going to be a Twitter.Request of course.
这将是一个Twitter。当然请求。
Request, optional, is not always set.
请求，可选，并不总是设置。
Everyone kinda see what I'm doing there?
大家都明白我在做什么吗?
And of course this is saying self again, so we'll put self
当然，这就是自我，所以我们把self
in there and of course self is weak so we'll do that.
在那里，当然，self很弱，所以我们这样做。
So that's all good.
这就是好。
Any other problems you can see with this?
还有其他问题吗?
I don't see any so far.
到目前为止我都没看到。
So it's all good. So,
所以一切都好。所以,
before we go hooking up our table view,
在我们连接表视图之前，
let's just make sure that our Twitter fetches are working.
让我们确保我们的Twitter取回正在工作。
And I'm gonna do that by putting a didSet
我要用didSet来做
up here on my model, and every time my model changes,
在我的模型上，每当我的模型改变时，
I'm just gonna print the tweets out.
我要把这些推文打印出来。
Now luckily I've made it so
幸运的是，我已经做到了
the tweet is CustomStringConvertible,
CustomStringConvertible推特,
it implements description.
它实现了描述。
It can print itself as a string so
它可以把自己打印成字符串
this is an array of those.
这是一个数组。
So this will print out an array, actually an array
这将打印出一个数组，实际上是一个数组
of an array of this tweet printed out as a string.
这条推特的数组以字符串形式打印出来。
So we're just gonna print it out there.
我们把它打印出来。
Just seems like it should work?
看起来应该行得通吗?
Let's go give it a try and find out.
让我们试着找出答案。
We'll do this on iPhone 7.
我们在iPhone 7上做这个。
Pay attention right now because this
现在就集中注意力
is not in fact going to work.
实际上并不是要去工作。
And this won't work for you either and you're gonna need
这对你也没用，你需要
to do a couple of things to make a Twitter fetch work.
做一些事情来做一个Twitter的取回工作。
By the way you see we have these prototype cells that
顺便说一下，我们看到了这些原型细胞
have to have reuse identifiers; gotta remember to
必须重新使用标识符;要记得
fix that later.
修复之后。
Alright, so we run, and look at this thing it puts up here,
好的，我们运行，看看它放在这里，
Smashtag would like to access Twitter accounts.
Smashtag希望访问Twitter账户。
So you're not allowed to write an app that just starts
所以你不允许写一个刚刚开始的应用
posting things for people on Twitter behind the scenes.
在幕后给人们发推特。
Okay, when you write an app it is always going to ask,
当你写一个应用时它总是会问，
the first time you try to use Twitter, whether it's allowed.
你第一次尝试使用Twitter，不管它是允许的。
So I'll click okay, and let's go look in our console and
点击ok，让我们看看控制台
see if it printed.
是否打印。
It didn't, all it printed out here is, couldn't discover
它打印出来的不是，没有发现
Twitter account type, hm, why would it say that?
推特账户类型，嗯，为什么这么说?
Well, that's because your simulator, it's just a device,
那是因为你的模拟器，它只是一个设备，
it needs to have Twitter, a Twitter account, basically,
它需要有Twitter，一个Twitter账号，
your device needs a Twitter account, so
你的设备需要一个Twitter帐户
where do we set that?
我们把它放在哪里?
So let's go back to our simulator,
我们回到模拟器，
here it is, I'm gonna go hardware, home button, okay,
这是，我要去硬件，home键，好的，
you can also do command, shift, F.
你也可以做命令，shift,F。
Is hardware home button.
是硬件按钮。
And I'm gonna go over to the Settings app on my simulator.
然后我要到模拟器上的设置应用程序。
But you can do it on your device as well.
但你也可以在你的设备上做。
And if you go down in settings, here's Twitter.
如果你在设置中，这里是Twitter。
Look at that.
看看这个。
Twitter right there.
Twitter。
And here's where you type in your
你在这里输入
Twitter username and password.
Twitter用户名和密码。
And if you don't type this in,
如果你不输入这个，
then no apps on your system can access Twitter.
你的系统上没有任何应用可以访问Twitter。
Cuz how would they- they'd have to know who you are.
因为他们要知道你是谁。
So I'm gonna type this here, I'm gonna do it off screen cuz
我要在这里输入，我要在屏幕上显示
I don't want you to see my password.
我不想让你看到我的密码。
So now I am logged in on Twitter.
所以现在我登录了Twitter。
So now if I go back and start my app
现在如果我回去开始我的应用程序
It will both be in allowed because I clicked OK.
它将会被允许，因为我点击OK。
And I'll be logged in so
我将会登陆
it'll have an actual Twitter user that can do it.
它会有一个真正的Twitter用户。
And sure enough, look down here at the bottom.
当然，向下看。
We're getting all kinds of tweets being printed out here.
我们在这里打印出各种各样的推文。
So here's a tweet.
这是一条微博。
Here's its unique ID.
这是其惟一的ID。
Here's the person who tweeted it.
这是推特的人。
Here's when it was tweeted.
这是推特的时候。
Here is the text of the tweet.
这是推特的文本。
This one's got an embedded URL, etc.
这个有一个嵌入的URL，等等。
So we're doing well.
所以我们做的很好。
We've got our tweets coming in.
我们已经收到了我们的tweets。
So now all we need to do is load them up into our
所以现在我们要做的就是把它们装进我们的
table view.
表视图。
So what do we need to do to load this thing up in
我们需要做什么来加载这个东西
the table view?
表视图?
Now, surprisingly simple actually, the two pieces we
其实很简单，这两个部分
have to do, one is every time we change our model we have
我们要做的是，每次我们改变我们的模型的时候
to tell the table view that it changed and then we have
告诉表视图，它改变了，然后我们有了
to implement those table view data source methods.
要实现这些表视图数据源方法。
So let's start with the first one.
我们从第一个开始。
Actually we have already changed our model once.
实际上，我们已经更改了我们的模型一次。
Right here, we changed our model and
在这里，我们改变了模型
we told the table view about it, so that's good.
我们告诉了表格视图，这很好。
Here we're changing our model.
我们要改变我们的模型。
So we need to tell the table view about it.
所以我们需要告诉表视图。
So self?.tableView.
所以自我? .tableView。
And what did I do here to my model?
我在模型中做了什么?
I just inserted a section at the beginning.
我刚开始插入一个部分。
So there happens to be a tableView method called
这里有一个tableView方法
insertSection.
insertSection。
And it just says, you inserted some sections.
它只是说，你插入了一些部分。
Which ones?
哪一个?
ask you about those and put the rows in there for you.
问你这些，把这些行放在那里。
I will go and
我将去
And this sections is an index set,
这部分是一个指数集，
which you can give it an array literal.
你可以给它一个数组的文字。
So I just inserted section zero.
所以我只是插入了section 0。
So I'll just put an array with just zero in it.
我把数组的值设为0。
And I'm gonna use the fade animation
我将使用渐变动画
to show that fading in.
显示它正在衰退。
So, insertSections.
所以,insertSections。
So, this is me telling the tableView, I changed my model,
这是我告诉tableView，我改变了模型，
so ask me again.
所以再次问我。
Ask me those tableView data source.
问我那些tableView的数据源。
Now, since I told it exactly what I did it's only gonna ask
现在，因为我告诉了它我所做的只是想问
me about that section, which is nice, higher performance.
我是关于那部分的，这很好，更高的性能。
Then reloadData, the hammer reloadData,
然后重载数据，重负荷数据，
in which case it would ask me for all rows in all sections
在这种情况下，它会要求我所有section中的所有行
again; so here I know exactly what I did.
再一次;所以我知道我做了什么。
Now this actually is dangerous code here.
这实际上是很危险的代码。
This is really easy to add this line of code and
这很容易添加这一行代码
now your app just acts weird.
现在你的应用程序就变得很奇怪了。
It just acts weird all the time.
它总是表现得很奇怪。
Can anyone, want, guess why this
有谁想知道为什么吗
adding this line of code would cause my app to go all weird?
添加这行代码会让我的应用程序变得很奇怪吗?
It's because this is a UI call.
因为这是一个UI调用。
And what queue are we on here?
这里有什么队列?
Some queue, not the main queue.
一些队列，而不是主队列。
Whatever queue we fetched those tweets on, okay?
无论我们在哪个队列上获取这些tweet，对吧?
So we're not on the main queue.
所以我们不在主队列上。
So we can't make a UI call here.
所以我们不能在这里做UI调用。
Right, so we have to dispatch this back to the main queue.
好的，我们必须将它发送回主队列。
So this is something that,
所以这是，
will just take some getting used to for
只是需要一些习惯吗
you guys with this multithreading,
有了多线程，
cuz you're gonna do these things in this other queue,
因为你要在另一个队列中做这些事情，
and you're gonna update your table view, and then
然后更新表格视图
it's like what's going on my app is just acting so strange.
这就像我的应用程序运行起来很奇怪。
And that's why- because you can do
这就是为什么——因为你能做到
UI stuff on the main queue.
主队列上的UI。
And it's not gonna warn you or necessarily crash,
它不会警告你或者必然会崩溃，
it might eventually crash, it's just gonna act all weird.
它可能最终会崩溃，它会表现得很奇怪。
So, fixed that.
所以,固定。
This is good.
这是很好的。
We've got the table view updating our model and we've
我们已经有了更新模型的表视图
got the table view knowing about change to the model.
了解了对模型的更改的表视图。
So now all we need to do is implement this
现在我们要做的就是实现这个
UITableViewDataSource protocol so
所以需要协议
that it can get the data from us.
它能从我们那里得到数据。
So let's do it.
让我们来做它。
Number of sections, how many sections are in our table?
section数，表中有多少个section ?
Anyone know?
有人知道吗?
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly, candy thrown at you cuz that's exactly right.
确切地说，糖果扔在你的身上，这完全正确。
tweets.count.
tweets.count。
It's just the number of arrays that we have in our model here
它只是我们模型中的数组的个数
because each of this arrays inside here are a section, so
因为这里的每个数组都是一个section
perfect.
完美的。
And then what about this one?
那么这个呢?
Here we're being asked how many rows are there in tweets
这里我们要问，推文中有多少行
subsection?
分段吗?
That's just count also.
这只是数也。
So we've designed our data structure so
所以我们设计了数据结构
that these are super easy to implement,
这些都非常容易实现，
which I highly recommend if you can do it.
如果你能做到，我强烈推荐。
You can't always do it.
你不能总是这么做。
But if you can it's nice.
但如果你能做到，那就太好了。
So now a little more difficult, only a little
所以现在有点困难，只有一点点
though, is cellForRowAt index path right here.
不过，这里是cellForRowAt索引路径。
So here's where we have to return the UITableViewCell
这是我们返回UITableViewCell的地方
that we're gonna use to draw.
我们要用它来画。
Now, let's go back to our Storyboard here and
现在，让我们回到我们的故事板
let's just start out with something simple.
我们从简单的开始。
Let's try using here a subtitle cell.
我们试着在这里使用一个subtitle单元格。
So I'm gonna click on this cell.
点击这个单元格。
And will change its style from being custom
并将改变它的风格
to being subtitle.
副标题。
So there's title and subtitle.
这里有标题和副标题。
And I'm gonna set the title to be the text with the tweet.
我将把标题设为tweet的文本。
And I'm gonna set the subtitle
我要设置副标题
to be the person who tweeted it.
成为推特的人。
So let's try that and see how that looks.
我们来试试看看。
So how am I gonna do that?
我要怎么做呢?
Two things I need to do here.
在这里我需要做两件事。
One is I need to dequeue a reusable cell, and
一个是我需要dequeue一个可重用的单元格，并且
I to tell iOS which prototype to use,
我告诉iOS要使用哪个原型，
which prototype in the Storyboard.
故事板中的原型。
So lets go back to our Storyboard.
让我们回到故事板。
And I only have one prototype.
我只有一个原型。
It's this one.
这是这一个。
That's the one I wanna use.
这是我想用的。
So I need to give it an identifier.
我需要给它一个标识符。
I'm gonna call it Tweet,
我把它叫做Tweet，
because that's what this cell shows.
因为这就是这个细胞所显示的。
It shows a tweet.
它显示了一个tweet。
Notice that caused my warning to go away.
注意，这引起了我的警告。
Because all these prototype cells
因为所有这些原型细胞
always need an identifier.
总是需要一个标识符。
And now when I go back here,
当我回到这里，
I can change this from reuseIdentifier to Tweet.
我可以从reuseIdentifier更改为Tweet。
Okay, so now, I am able to dequeueReusableCell
好了，现在，我可以dequeueReusableCell了
that will be a copy of that prototype that's subtitled.
那将会是这个原型的拷贝，副标题。
So all my rows are gonna be subtitle rows.
所以所有的行都是副标题行。
So now I've got this cell,
现在我有了这个单元格，
it's of type UITableViewCell by the way,
顺便说一下，它是UITableViewCell，
since it's a standard type not a custom type.
因为它是标准类型，而不是自定义类型。
How do I configure it?
我如何配置它?
Well, for me to configure the cells, to set the title and
对我来说，配置单元格，设置标题
I need to know which Tweet it's asking me for here.
我需要知道在这里问我的是哪条推文。
the subtitle,
副标题,
And I know which Tweet it's asking because it's
我知道是哪条推文，因为它是
saying cellForRowAt.
说cellForRowAt。
This is the row that's the tweet that is asking
这是这条推文
me to give it a UITableViewCell for.
我给它一个UITableViewCell。
So I'm gonna let tweet equal
所以我要让tweet等于
my model sub indexPath.section and
我的模型子indexPath。节和
indexPath.row.
indexpath。row。
So I'm just getting this row in this section,
所以我在这一部分得到这一行，
this gets the first array, the section,
这得到第一个数组，section，
I'm just getting the row out of it.
我只是把它弄出来。
So now I got the tweet, so now I can just update the cell
现在我得到了tweet，所以现在我可以更新单元格了
really easily, cell.textLabel.
真的很容易,cell.textLabel。
It might be an optional ?.text equals,
它可能是可选的?文本=,
let's have that be the tweet's text.
让我们把它变成推特的文本。
This is something that you'll see in here, we go to
这是你们在这里看到的，我们去
the Twitter, and look for the Twitter framework at Tweet,
推特，在推特上寻找推特框架，
and you'll see that the very first one in fact, is text.
你会看到，第一个是文本。
And then we'll make this cell detailTextLabel,
然后我们将创建这个cell detailTextLabel，
its text will be the tweet's user's name, let's say.
它的文本将是推特用户的名字。
So again, Tweet, user, username.
再一次，推特，用户，用户名。
So, that's why I'm getting that information.
这就是我得到这些信息的原因。
Do you understand that?
你明白吗?
Part of it, okay?
它的一部分,好吗?
So, that I'll came out of this Tweet.
所以，我将从这条推文中出来。
This is of type Tweet.
这是推特的类型。
Everybody got that?
大家都明白了吗?
All right, so is that it?
好吧，是这样吗?
Do we need to do anything else to hook this thing up and
我们需要做些什么来把这个东西勾起来吗
make it work?
让它工作吗?
Turns out no.
结果没有。
So let's just run.
让我们来运行。
Okay, there it is.
好的,就是这样。
The world's greatest Twitter client.
世界上最伟大的Twitter客户。
Look at that.
看看这个。
It looks beautiful.
它看起来很漂亮。
No, of course, in fact,
不，当然，事实上，
this is the world's ugliest Twitter client right here.
这是世界上最丑的Twitter客户端。
But it is working.
但这是工作。
These are tweets.
这些都是微博。
But anyway, you can see here's the tweets and
无论如何，你可以看到这里的推文和
here are the person who tweeted it.
这是推特的人。
Now obviously, this is awful UI.
很明显，这是糟糕的UI。
Just absolutely horrendous UI.
是绝对可怕的UI。
You would never have a Twitter client like this.
你永远不会有这样的Twitter客户。
We want our UI in these cells to look much nicer,
我们想让我们的UI在这些单元格里看起来更好，
much more customized to a tweet.
更定制的推特。
So we're gonna go back to our Storyboard here.
我们回到这里的故事板。
And instead of using this awful subtitle style cell,
而不是使用这个可怕的字幕样式单元，
we're gonna build a custom cell.
我们将构建一个自定义单元格。
And this custom cell is gonna have more good looking and
这个自定义单元格会有更好的外观
more of the data that comes with a Tweet.
更多的数据来自推特。
So let's just build it.
我们来建立它。
Let's go here and make this a little bigger, make some room.
让我们把它放大一些，腾出点空间。
All right, I'm gonna grab some labels out of here.
好吧，我把标签拿出来。
There's a label, this will maybe be,
有一个标签，可能是，
let's say this is the Tweeter.
假设这是推特。
This is the person who's doing the Tweet.
这是做推特的人。
By the way, this is a case where we're showing user
顺便说一下，这是一个我们展示用户的例子
content really.
真正的内容。
These tweets are content.
这些微博内容。
They're not like the title of a button or something,
它们不像按钮的标题，
it's actually the content that the user has requested to see.
它实际上是用户要求看到的内容。
So I'm gonna use a font here.
这里我要用一个字体。
You see this font?
你看到这个字体吗?
I'm not gonna use the system font.
我不会使用系统字体。
I'm going to go down and start using this text styles.
我要开始使用文本样式。
So the Tweeter is going to be at the top.
所以Tweeter将会在顶部。
I'm gonna have that be a headline font.
我要用标题字体。
So this is gonna be the headline font and
这是标题字体
this could change over time, okay, whatever the system
这可能会随着时间改变，不管系统是什么
thinks headline font is and it'll be true in every app.
认为标题字体在每个应用程序都是正确的。
The headline will always be using this font in every app
标题总是在每个应用程序中使用这种字体
and users could even go into settings and
用户甚至可以进入设置
change the size of their fonts.
改变字体的大小。
If they're like me and
如果他们像我一样
they're visions going they can set them bigger.
他们认为他们可以让他们更大。
And the fonts will get bigger automatically so
字体会自动变大
ther's big advantage to using these font styles.
使用这些字体样式有很大的优势。
So there's that one.
这是那一个。
There is the text of the tweet itself, so
这就是推特本身的文本
we'll just call that text.
我们把它叫做文本。
maybe a good font is body font because this is really, this
也许一个好的字体是体字体，因为这是真的
For this one,
为了这一个,
is the heart of what we're doing here, this body thing.
是我们在这里做的，这个身体的核心。
One thing that's kinda cool with UILabel, the text
有一件事对UILabel很酷，就是文本
in the tweet is probably gonna be multiple lines, and
在推特上可能会有多条线路
it's gonna wrap.
它会结束。
When you have a UI label like that,
当你有一个这样的UI标签时，
you wanna set this property lines to be zero.
你想把这个属性设为0。
If you have zero predefined lines then the UILabel
如果没有预先定义的线那么UILabel
will be however many lines it needs to be fit
然而，它需要多少线才能合适
the information with wrapping.
与包装的信息。
Whereas this one is line one this all one line.
而这条线是一条线。
And if it's too long it just gets dot dot dot at the end,
如果它太长它就会在最后得到。
all right?
好吧?
What else do I wanna do here?
我还想做什么?
Let's do another label here for
我们再做一个标记
when the tweet was tweeted out, when it was created.
当推特发布时，它被创建了。
That one is probably something like a caption, we'll say.
这可能是一个标题，我们会说。
Small little text at the bottom.
小的文字在底部。
We'll go ahead and center than right there.
我们先把中心放在这里。
Let's also get an image.
我们也可以得到一个图像。
Let's go down and find the image view down here.
我们往下走，在下面找到图像视图。
Where is our image view?
我们的图像视图在哪里?
Here it is.
在这儿。
Drag it out here. This is gonna be the profile
拖出来。这就是个人资料
image of the Tweeter.
推特的形象。
So whoever tweeted this will have their little image here.
无论谁在推特上都有自己的小形象。
This one, by the way,
顺便说一下，
I don't know how big profile images are on Twitter.
我不知道在Twitter上有多大的个人形象。
And I don't care because I'm gonna make this thing
我不在乎因为我要做这个
always be a fixed size.
永远是固定的尺寸。
So how do we make an image like this be a fixed size
我们怎样做一个像这样的图像是固定大小的
using auto layout?
使用自动布局?
And it turns out what you do is you Ctrl+Drag to itself.
你所做的就是按Ctrl +拖动。
And when you do,
当你做什么,
you'll see that you have the option to fix its width.
您将看到您可以选择修改它的宽度。
And you can Ctrl+Drag, and fix its height.
你可以Ctrl +拖动，调整它的高度。
You can also to both at the same time.
你也可以同时兼顾两者。
And, so what width and height has it fixed it to?
那么它的宽度和高度是多少?
Well, we can look over here in the size inspector,
我们可以看看尺寸检查器，
and see that it's fixed it to 71 by 67.
把它固定到71 / 67。
That doesn't sound very computer science-y,
这听起来并不像计算机科学，
I'm gonna fix it to 64 by 64.
我把它固定到64 / 64。
So I've made it so
所以我已经做到了
this image view is always gonna be 64 by 64.
图像视图总是64比64。
I don't care how big the person's actual profile image
我不关心这个人的真实形象有多大
is, I always want it to be that way.
是，我一直希望它是那样的。
Okay, so there's another little auto layout
还有一个小的自动布局
tidbit for you.
一点线索。
speaking of auto layouts, I need to lay this stuff out.
说到汽车布局，我需要把这些东西放出来。
All right, so
好吧,那么
I kinda want it to look, eh, something like this.
我想让它看起来，嗯，像这样。
See what I mean?
明白我的意思吗?
Approximately, and so I'm just gonna use stack view.
大约，我将使用堆栈视图。
So we'll stack those two things together, like that.
我们把这两种东西堆叠在一起，像这样。
Look at our things here, fill and fill.
看看我们的东西，填满它。
That's perfectly fine.
就很好了。
Let's go over here.
我们去这里。
Let's stack those together.
让我们一起堆那些。
That's fill and fill.
这是填补和充实。
One thing about these two, by the way, they're gonna be
顺便说一下，关于这两个问题，有一点是肯定的
sharing the space in this stack view equally.
在堆栈视图中平均共享空间。
But I don't want them sharing equally.
但我不想让他们平均分享。
I actually want the text to get more of this space.
实际上，我希望文本能得到更多的空间。
So I'm gonna click on the Tweeter.
点击推特。
And I'm gonna go over to this size inspector.
我要去找尺寸检查器。
And I'm gonna do something cool,
我要做一些很酷的事，
which is set its content hugging priority.
它的内容被设定为“拥抱优先”。
I'm gonna set its vertical content
我要设置它的垂直内容
hugging priority to be higher than the other one.
拥抱优先权比另一个要高。
So they're both 251.
所以他们都是251。
You see, that one's 251, that one's 251.
你看，那个是251，那个是251。
So I'm gonna set this one to be 300,
所以我要把这个设为300，
just anything higher than 251.
只要高于251就可以了。
And that means that when the space is being allocated
这意味着，当空间被分配时
between this tweeter and
这个推特和
the text, it's gonna hug the tweeter's content.
文本，它将会拥抱tweeter的内容。
And the text is gonna get all the rest.
而文本将会得到所有的结果。
So that's a way that you can kinda,
这是一种方法，
when you're sharing space between two things.
当你在两个事物之间共享空间的时候。
All right, so now let's put these two in a stack.
好，现在我们把这两个放到堆栈里。
Maybe we'll put some spacing here, something like that.
也许我们会在这里放一些空间，像这样。
Alignment here, top is good, I want them both at the top.
在这里对齐，顶部很好，我想让它们都在顶部。
I think that's good, lined up at the top.
我认为这很好，排在前面。
If I like that and fill is fine, I've got this.
如果我喜欢这个，填充没问题，我有这个。
Now I'm gonna do the same thing we did before,
现在我要做和之前一样的事情，
which is I'm gonna put this in the corner.
我要把它放在角落里。
And I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the top.
然后Ctrl拖动到顶部。
I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the leading edge.
Ctrl拖动到前边。
I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the trailing edge.
我将按Ctrl拖动到拖尾边缘。
And I'm gonna Ctrl drag to the bottom edge.
然后Ctrl拖动到底部边缘。
So I want that out there.
我想把它写出来。
And again, the same thing.
同样的。
I'm gonna take this and change it to standard if I can.
如果可以的话，我要把这个改成标准。
I can't, so we'll go 0.
我不能，所以我们要0。
And same thing here.
这里同样的事情。
Standard if I can, can't, we'll do 0.
如果我能，不能，我们将做0。
So I've made this stock view that contains all
我做了一个包含所有的股票视图
the stuff fit in there.
里面有东西。
So I basically done the auto layout necessary to make this
所以我基本上完成了制作这个的自动布局
thing use the space properly.
物体适当地利用空间。
And I can still change the size of the cell, all right?
我仍然可以改变细胞的大小?
I can click on it and I can make it a little bit smaller
我可以点击它，我可以让它变小一点
and all that stuff is going to, you know,
所有这些，你知道，
stick to the edges, so that'll be fine.
粘在边上，这样就好了。
Now, this is great,
现在,这是伟大的,
in fact if we go back to our table view controller and
事实上，如果我们回到我们的表视图控制器
if I comment out this cell configuration because we don't
如果我把这个单元格说出来，因为我们没有
have a subtitle so these don't make any sense any more.
有一个副标题，所以这些没有任何意义。
And we run, then we gonna see that our UI hopefully,
然后我们运行，然后看到我们的UI希望，
if we didn't forget anything.
如果我们什么都没忘记。
It's going to look in some ways a little better.
它会以某种方式看起来更好一些。
Yeah, so it kinda looks better.
嗯，看起来好多了。
Now, the only thing that's not better is we lost our data
现在，唯一没有更好的是我们丢失了数据
because I commented out the data loading right here.
因为我在这里注释了数据加载。
So this is what we want UI to look like basically with
这就是我们想要的UI
an image here and that there.
这是一个图像。
But we need to set all this data.
但我们需要设置所有这些数据。
So how do we that?
那我们该怎么做呢?
Since this is a custom cell over here.
因为这里是自定义单元格。
We have to do with a custom subclass
我们必须使用自定义子类
of this UI table view cell right here.
这个uitableviewcell。
So, I'm gonna create one of those, New File.
我要创建一个新文件。
Let's go here and New File.
让我们来这里看看新文件。
Again, Cocoa Touch Class; this time though,
再次,可可触摸类;这一次,
it's not a TableViewController it's a TableViewCell.
它不是一个TableViewController它是一个TableViewCell。
I'm gonna call it TweetTableViewCell cuz
我把它命名为TweetTableViewCell cuz
it shows the tweet,
它显示了微博,
put in the same place as all the rest of my stuff there.
把我剩下的东西放在同一个地方。
Here's my table table view cell, it gives me awakeFromNib
这是我的表视图单元格，它给我awakeFromNib
which is kinda nice but I don't need it and setSelected
这很好，但我不需要它和setSelected
I don't do anything special when my table view cell is
当我的表格视图单元格时，我没有做任何特别的事情
selected but I could, I could draw a blue background or
选择但我可以，我可以画一个蓝色背景
something like that if I wanted, but I don't.
如果我想要这样的东西，但我没有。
So, I have this TableViewCell subclass.
我有这个TableViewCell子类。
I'm gonna go back to my Storyboard and
回到我的故事板
make sure that I set the identity,
确认我设置了身份，
don't forget this step.
别忘了这一步。
Set the identity to be a TweetTableViewCell.
将身份设置为TweetTableViewCell。
If you forget this step,
如果你忘了这一步，
you won't be able to do any outlets or anything like that.
你不能做任何出口或类似的事情。
Now, I wanna wire outlets up to this new class I
现在，我想把outlet到这个新的类I
just created, so I need to get them both on screen,
刚刚创建，所以我需要在屏幕上，
I'll show you kind of a cool way to do that.
我会给你们展示一种很酷的方法。
Let's get the assistant editor up here,
让我们来看看助理编辑，
remember I could do manual, blah, blah, blah,
记住，我可以用手动，等等，等等，
but another way is to hold down the option key, and
但另一种方法是按住option键，然后
just click on the thing that you want to be on the right,
只要点击你想要在右边的东西，
I think I showed this before, but option
我想我之前展示过，但是选项
clicking in the navigator will put that thing on the right.
在导航器中单击将把这个东西放在右边。
All right so let's move this over more, some space there.
好的，让我们把这个移到更多的地方。
All right, so I need to wire up outlets to these four
好的，我需要把outlet到这四个
things, right, the tweet or the text or the image.
内容，正确，推文，文字或图片。
So let's just do that.
我们来做一下。
We'll go here, Ctrl+drag,
我们就去这里,Ctrl +拖,
screen out, I'll call this my tweet, what did I call this,
屏幕外，我把这叫做我的推特，我叫它什么来着，
my tweetProfileImageView.
我的tweetProfileImageView。
Cuz it's gonna be a UIImageView that shows
因为它将是一个UIImageView
the Tweeter's profile.
推特的概要文件。
Let's do the little create down here,
让我们在这里做一些创建，
Ctrl+Drag, from that.
Ctrl +拖,。
We'll call that tweetCreatedLabel.
我们称之为tweetCreatedLabel。
To label it.
标签。
Shows when it was created; let's do out little tweeter
显示它是何时创建的;我们来做小推特
right here and we call that our tweetUserLabel,
在这里，我们称它为tweetUserLabel，
this is gonna show the label of the tweet
这将显示推文的标签
user and then we have the text right here that's gonna show
用户，然后我们有文本，它会显示
the actual tweetText, tweetTextLabel.
实际tweetText tweetTextLabel。
So I've got these nice little outlets right here.
这里有一些漂亮的小插座。
Now of course I need to be able to set these outlets with
当然，我需要能够设置这些outlet
something and here's where I need public API in my
这是我需要公共API的地方
table view cell, that gives me the data I need to do that.
表格视图单元格，它给了我需要的数据。
And I'm just going to have my public API be tweet,
我将把我的公共API推到twitter上，
give me the Twitter.Tweet that you want and
给我推特。你想要的推特
I'll load these babies up.
我要把这些孩子装上。
That's what it's saying here.
这就是它的意思。
Of course we need to import Twitter.
当然，我们需要导入Twitter。
Cuz we're using it in this class.
因为我们在课堂上使用它。
And when you set this Tweet I'm just going to on didSet.
当你设置这条推特的时候，我将会在didSet上。
Update my UI just like I was a controller but
更新我的UI就像我是控制器一样
I'm not, I'm not a controller, I'm a view actually.
我不是，我不是控制器，我是一个视图。
It's the only time a view can have these outlets.
这是唯一一个视图可以拥有这些outlet的时间。
So I need some private func to do that updateUI.
所以我需要一些私有的func来完成updateUI。
Now, time is running a little bit short here, so
现在，时间有点短了
I'm just going to type this in real quick
我很快就会把它打出来
I believe I have tweet cell.
我相信我有推特细胞。
There it is, okay?
在这里,好吗?
But you can look at this later.
但你可以以后再看这个。
But I'm just basically setting all the outlets here.
但我只是在这里设置所有的outlet。
See how I'm just setting these outlets like setting the tweet
看看我是如何设置这些媒体的，比如设置推特
label, text to be the tweet's text,
标签，文本为推文的文本，
setting the user label to be the user description.
将用户标签设置为用户描述。
Notice by the way I'm blocking the main thread here.
注意，我挡住了主线程。
If this was my homework, bam I just got dinged.
如果这是我的作业，我就被圈住了。
So make sure you fix this, okay?
所以一定要解决这个问题，好吗?
If you're gonna use my code in any way in your homework,
如果你要在作业中使用我的代码，
which you probably want to,
你可能想，
then you're gonna wanna fix this.
然后你要解决这个问题。
Don't do this on the main thread.
在主线程上不要这样做。
Don't block the main thread.
不要阻塞主线程。
But, does anyone understand what updateUI is doing here?
但是，有人知道updateUI在这里做什么吗?
It's just taking this Tweet that I was giving,
这是我发的这条推文，
and loading this up.
和加载。
And this is happening over and over for
这是不断发生的
every row in the table that gets displayed.
表中的每一行都显示出来。
This is happening, the copy of this class has been made and
这发生了，这个类的副本已经完成了
this is happening.
这是发生。
Now, how do we set this?
现在，我们怎么来设置这个呢?
We set this back over here and our TweetTableViewController.
我们在这里设回TweetTableViewController。
In the same place that we configured the cell here for
我们在这里配置了这个单元格
the subtitle one.
副标题。
And in fact, I still need the tweet, but I don't need that.
事实上，我仍然需要这条推文，但我不需要它。
I'll leave those there, so
我把这些留在那里
you can remember that code when you look at it later.
当您稍后查看它时，您可以记住这些代码。
But instead of setting those things, I just want
而不是设置这些东西，我只是想要
to set that tweet, I wanna set this var right here.
要设置这个tweet，我要在这里设置这个var。
But for me to set the var right here,
但我要在这里设置var，
I need to get my table view to be one of these.
我需要让我的表格视图成为其中之一。
So, I need to use an as.
因此，我需要使用as。
So, I'm gonna say,
所以,我想说,
if I can let the tweetCell equal the cell,
如果我能让tweetCell等于cell，
this reusable cell that I got, as a TweetTableViewCell,
这个可重复使用的单元，作为TweetTableViewCell，
then, I can say, cell set your tweet to be my tweet.
然后，我可以说，cell设置你的tweet为我的tweet。
That goes in this row, section, and row.
它在这一行，section，和row中。
Now, we set the, what, sorry, tweetCell.tweet.
现在，我们设置，抱歉，tweetcell. tweet。
We set the class of these, of this prototype right here,
我们在这里设置了这个原型，
the prototype for this cell.
这个单元格的原型。
We set it with the identity
我们把它设置为恒等式
inspector to be a TweetTableViewCell.
视察员是一个TweetTableViewCell。
So, when we come in here, it will, in fact,
所以当我们来到这里的时候，
this as will work.
这是将工作。
Okay, it will be a TweetTableViewCell cuz we said
它将是一个TweetTableViewCell cuz
that in the Storyboard, so, it created that kind of thing,
在故事板中，它创建了这样的东西，
all right?
好吧?
So, let see if this works.
所以，让我们看看它是否有效。
Okay, it is working.
好吧,这是工作。
Look, we've got the time the person tweeted this,
看，我们有时间在推特上，
it's got the person who tweeted it,
是有人在推特上发的，
it's got the text of the tweeting, but we get no image.
它有推特的文本，但我们没有图像。
Why didn't we get people's images here?
为什么我们没有在这里得到人们的图像呢?
Okay, why do you think we didn't get these,
好吧，为什么你认为我们没有得到这些，
these images?
这些图片吗?
Well, let's go look at our console.
我们来看看控制台。
What does it say?
它说什么了?
No!
不!
App Transport Security.
应用交通安全。
You recognize that from last time?
你能从上节课看到吗?
It's because these profiles are http something not
这是因为这些概要文件不是http
https something.
https。
So, we know how to fix that.
我们知道怎么解决这个问题。
We'll just go back to Info.plist right here.
我们会回到信息。plist。
And add a row for App Transport Security.
并为应用程序传输安全性添加一行。
We'll open that up, we'll add Arbitrary Loads here,
我们打开它，我们在这里添加任意的负载，
we'll make that be, yes, we allow arbitrary loads.
我们会让它成为，是的，我们允许任意载荷。
There's another problem here though.
不过这里还有一个问题。
Look at all these tweets.
看看这些推文。
Look how they're cut off, you see?
看看它们是怎么被切断的，明白吗?
Every row is the same size and it's not big enough for
每一行都是一样的大小，而且还不够大
most of the tweets.
大部分的tweet。
It's just dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot.
就是点，点，点，点，点。
Wouldn't it be cool if these rows could be different sizes
如果这些行可以是不同的尺寸，那不是很酷吗
depending on how big the tweet is?
取决于这条推文有多大?
Well, of course we can do that.
当然我们可以这么做。
Let's do it.
让我们做它。
Let's go see how this size is being said right now.
让我们看看这个尺寸是怎么说的。
Right now, it's being said, if we go and
现在，有人说，如果我们去
inspect this cell in its size inspector, look,
检查它的尺寸检查器，看，
the row height is 96, so, every single row is 96.
行高是96，所以每一行都是96。
What we wanna do is in our viewDidLoad right here,
我们要做的是在viewDidLoad中，
we wanna say that our tableView's row height is not
我们想说tableView的行高度不是
96, it's UITableViewAutomaticDimension.
But as I said before, we also want to give it a little help
但正如我之前说过的，我们也想给它一点帮助
by setting its estimated row height to something.
通过将其估计的行高度设置为某些东西。
And I'll tell you what,
我告诉你，
let's set it to what's in the Storyboard.
我们把它设置成故事板中的内容。
tableView.rowHeight, okay?
表视图。rowHeight,好吗?
So, I'm getting the rowHeight out of the Storyboard,
我从故事板中得到rowh8，
using it as the estimate.
用它作为估计值。
And then, I'm resetting
然后,我重置
the rowHeight to be the AutomaticDimension.
rowh8是自动机。
And sure enough, see, look,
当然，看，
this tall tweet is getting extra space and
这条高推特正在获得额外的空间
some of the smaller tweets, I don't know if we have any,
一些较小的推文，我不知道我们是否有，
you can probably see it if we go like this.
如果我们这样做，你可能会看到它。
The smaller tweets get less space, okay?
较小的推文得到的空间更少?
So, that's good.
所以,这很好。
We're out of time, so, if you have to go, feel free.
我们没时间了，所以，如果你要去的话，感觉自由。
The last thing I'm gonna do here in a little over time is
随着时间的推移，我最后要做的是
add a text field at the top that lets us type in what
在顶部添加一个文本字段，让我们输入什么
we wanna search for instead of always looking for Stanford.
我们想要寻找，而不是一直寻找斯坦福。
So, we're gonna get Stanford out of there, okay?
所以，我们要把斯坦福赶出去，好吗?
So, how do we do that?
那么，我们该怎么做呢?
It's real easy.
这是真的很容易。
We have, if you remember,
如果你们还记得的话，
the table view, it's got this little header view at the top.
表视图，顶部有一个小标题视图。
So, I'm just gonna take a UITextField.
我将使用UITextField。
Remember this editable text field we learned about in
请记住我们所了解的可编辑文本字段
the last lecture?
上节课吗?
And I'm gonna put it on the top.
我把它放在上面。
It's a little hard, sometimes, to see where it's going,
这有点难，有时候，看它的方向，
but when it looks like this, the width of the table, then,
但当它看起来像这样的时候，桌子的宽度，
you've got it, it's dropping it in there.
你已经得到了它，它正在把它扔到那里。
It's also a little hard to select and click on.
选择和点击也有点困难。
So, you're gonna wanna use that Ctrl + Shift + Click.
你要用Ctrl + Shift + Click。
And that way, you can pick either the controller, or
这样，你可以选择控制器，或者
the table view, or in this case, the text field.
表视图，在本例中是文本字段。
I'm gonna inspect it and change it a little bit.
我要检查一下，然后稍微改变一下。
I'm just gonna make the font a little bit bigger,
我把字体放大一点，
we'll say 22.
我们会说22。
Now, notice I can also set all those text field things I was
注意，我还可以设置所有的文本字段
talking about.
说什么。
Like, I don't want it auto-correcting.
比如，我不希望它自动纠错。
I don't wanna say, search for hashtag SuperBowl and
我不想说，搜索hashtag SuperBowl和
change it hashtag SuperSpaceBowl, okay?
把它改成hashtag SuperSpaceBowl，好吗?
So, I don't want any correction going on.
所以，我不希望发生任何更正。
Keyboard type, ooh, look,
键盘类型:哦,看,
there's a Twitter keyboard type.
有一个推特键盘类型。
It's probably got # and @ sign, things like that.
可能有# @符号之类的。
The return key,
返回键,
that's just the key on the things says return.
这就是问题的关键所在。
I'm searching here, so, I wanted to say search.
我在这里搜索，所以，我想说搜索。
So, that means the return keys gonna say, I'd search.
这意味着返回键会说，我搜索。
Also, a little clear button would be cool,
另外，一个小的按钮会很酷，
button you can press the clear out what's going on.
你可以按下这个按钮。
So, you can kinda configure this in any way you want
你可以用任何你想要的方式来配置它
to make it work in there.
让它在那里工作。
Now, normally I would run this and show you that it's there,
现在，通常我会运行这个并告诉你它在那里，
let's wire it up first, so, it actually does something.
让我们先把它连接起来，它确实做了一些事情。
but of course,
当然,
It's real easy to wire up a text field if you just
如果你只是想把文本框连接起来很容易
wanna hook it up to an outlet and set its delegate, and
想要把它连接到一个outlet并设置它的委托，并且
then, you can find out when the return key is pressed.
然后，您可以发现返回键何时被按下。
So, let's do that.
所以,让我们这样做。
We'll go here, let's get our TweetTableViewController on
我们到这里，让我们打开TweetTableViewController
screen at the same time.
屏幕同时显示。
We just wanna create an outlet to that thing.
我们只是想创建一个outlet到那个东西。
I'll put it, right in here.
我把它放在这里。
So, I'm just,
所以,我只是
again, I will probably wanna Shift + Click to select it.
再一次，我可能想要移动+点击来选择它。
I, oops, picked the wrong one.
我选错了。
So, let's Shift + Click, click this, select this,
所以，让我们移动+点击，点击这个，选择这个，
and Ctrl + Drag from it, and see it's a UITextField, and
然后按住Ctrl +拖动，看到它是UITextField
I'm gonna call this my searchTextField.
我把它命名为searchTextField。
Simple as that.
就这么简单。
When it's set, I'm going to set myself as its delegates.
当它设置时，我将把自己设为它的代表。
searchTextField.delegate = self.
searchTextField。委托=自我。
Of course, for me to be its delegate, I have to go
当然，我要成为它的代表，我得走了
up here and say yes, I am a UITextFieldDelegate.
在这里，说“是”，我是一个UITextFieldDelegate。
Okay, they're all the methods are optional in there, so,
它们都是可选的，
I have now successfully implemented that protocol.
现在，我已经成功地实现了这个协议。
Ooh, what happened here?
哦,发生了什么?
Yes, okay, so that's so I've set the delegate.
好的，这就是我设置的委托。
Now, I'm gonna implement the delegate method I want,
现在，我要实现我想要的委托方法，
which is that should return.
这是应该返回的。
It get sent to me when the return button is sent.
当返回按钮被发送时，它被发送给我。
So that is textField,
这是文本框,
notice as I type textField it shows me them all,
当我输入textField的时候，它显示了所有的，
and it is this one right here textFieldShouldReturn.
就是这个textFieldShouldReturn。
Let me make this bigger, bigger so
我把它放大一点
you can see it better.
你能看得更好。
Okay, so here should return.
好的，这里应该返回。
If I get return, I'm actually gonna check to make
如果我得到了回报，我将会进行检查
sure I'm getting this from my searchTextField,
我从searchTextField得到这个，
because someday I might have other text fields and I wanna
因为有一天我可能会有其他文本框，我想
make sure I'm getting, I know which one I'm talking about.
确保我能得到，我知道我说的是哪一个。
So textField is this argument right here, and
textField就是这个参数
I'm just checking to make sure it's me.
我只是想确认一下是不是我。
And if that is true then I'm just gonna set my
如果这是真的，那么我将设置我的
searchText = searchTextFields.text, okay?
searchText = searchTextFields。文本,好吗?
Makes sense and when I set my searchText,
讲得通，当我设置搜索文本时，
that's immediately going to start it going.
马上就要开始了。
Notice that ShouldReturn also returns a Bool which is
注意，ShouldReturn也会返回一个Bool
whether to do what it normally does when return is pressed.
在按下时，是否做正常的工作。
Which in this case is nothing,
在这种情况下，
cuz we don't have any target action or
因为我们没有任何目标行动
anything else, but we'll return true.
其他的，但我们会返回真值。
Sure do what you normally do, now the only other thing
当然做你平常做的事，现在唯一的事
here is now that we have the searchTextField,
现在我们有了searchTextField，
up here when we set our searchText.
当我们设置搜索文本的时候。
We wanna update our searchTextField.
我们想更新searchTextField。
And I'll be careful here in case I'm doing it in prepare.
我要小心，以防我在准备。
We'll set it to the searchText that we just set it to.
我们将它设置为我们刚刚设置的searchText。
Also I'm going to have my searchTextField
还有我的searchTextField
resignFirstResponder here.
resignFirstResponder这里。
That's if somebody types something and hits go search,
那就是如果有人输入东西并点击搜索，
and we search for something and put it in there.
我们搜索一些东西并把它放在那里。
I'm gonna take the keyboard away.
我要把键盘拿走。
Cuz I just don't wanna have the keyboard blocking
因为我不想让键盘挡住
the results that they just asked for.
他们所要求的结果。
And also someone sets it in code.
还有人把它设置成代码。
I'm gonna get rid of keyboard.
我要删掉键盘了。
Someone might be in the middle of typing but
可能有人正在打字，但是
if someone sets it in code rather than typing.
如果有人把它设置成代码而不是键入。
Let's get that keyboard out of the way, all right?
让我们把那个键盘挪开，好吗?
So let's go do that.
我们来做一下。
Leave this code on the screen so you can see it.
把这些代码留在屏幕上，这样您就可以看到它了。
All right, so here is our text field, it's kinda of hard to
好的，这是我们的文本框，有点难
see under this carrier, we'll fix that in a second.
看看这个载体，我们马上就能解决这个问题。
Let's go and search for #stanford again.
让我们再来搜索# stanford。
Oops, I'm not gonna do this, watch this.
我不会这么做，看这个。
Okay that looked easy to type, didn't it?
看起来很容易打字，不是吗?
Well let's go here and
我们来看看
say Keyboard, turn off the hardware keyboard.
说键盘，关掉硬件键盘。
Now when we click in here,
当我们点击这里，
ooh, it's a lot harder to type.
哦，打字要难得多。
#stanford, okay so now you're getting into what
I'm saying about learn to type like your users will be.
我想说的是，学会像你的用户一样打字。
So here I'm going to search, goes in stanford and
我将在斯坦福进行搜索
search for it.
寻找它。
Let's go and search for something else here.
我们去搜索别的东西吧。
Maybe we'll search for,
也许我们会寻找,
this is kind of dangerous because people might say, but
这很危险，因为人们可能会说，但是
Trump >> Okay,
特朗普> >好的,
there's some Trump ones.
有一些胜过的。
Now, we've done all this.
现在，我们已经做了所有这些。
I wanna fix this thing though,
我想解决这个问题，
where this looks really bad at the top here.
这看起来很糟糕。
And there's this really easy fix to that.
这个问题很容易解决。
Which is I'm just going to, this is the fix.
我要讲的是，这是一个修正。
The fix is everything in the UI as you've learned.
在UI中，修复就是你学过的所有东西。
I'm just gonna embed this in a navigation controller.
我将把它嵌入到导航控制器中。
Okay, when you embed this in a navigation controller and run,
当你将它嵌入到导航控制器中并运行时，
you can see that it makes a nice title at the top,
你可以看到它在顶部有一个很好的标题，
it moves the text field down,
它移动文本框，
it's just much nicer all around.
到处都很好。
Okay, see how it has done that from a bit down here.
好的，看看它是怎么做到的。
One other thing I'm gonna do is put placeholder text in
我要做的另一件事是把占位符文本放进去
there, I meant to show you that.
在那里，我想告诉你。
Sorry, let's do that, if I go back to here click this.
抱歉，我们这样做，如果我回到这里，点击这个。
That thing in here, swipe this guide.
在这里，滑动这个指南。
You can put a placeholder text like this, Twitter Search and
你可以设置一个这样的占位符，Twitter搜索和
see it shows it in there, kinda like gray.
看它显示在那里，有点像灰色。
So that when you run, it's more obvious to the user,
所以当你运行时，它对用户来说更明显，
what is that big white space, all right?
那个大的空白区域是什么?
Be clear to them that it's a Twitter search.
让他们明白这是一个Twitter搜索。
You know all you need to know to do your homework.
你知道你需要做的所有功课。
Good luck with it.
祝你好运。
>> For more, please visit us at Stanford.edu.
>> 更多课程详见 stanford.edu